<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!--
	© 2013 Open Data Institute
	This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 2.0 UK: England & Wales License.
	http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/2.0/uk/deed.en_GB
  -->
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../surveyor.xsl"?>
<questionnaire version="1.0" status="final" jurisdiction="GB" xml:lang="en">
	<help>
		<p>This self-assessment questionnaire generates an open data certificate and badge you can publish to tell people all about this open data. We also use your answers to learn how organisations publish open data.</p>
		<p>When you answer these questions it demonstrates your efforts to comply with relevant UK legislation. You should also check which other laws and policies apply to your sector, especially if you’re outside the UK (which these questions don’t cover).</p>
		<p><strong>You do not need to answer all the questions to get a certificate.</strong> Just answer those you can.</p>
	</help>
	<group id="legal">
		<label>Legal Information</label>
		<help>Rights, licensing and privacy</help>
		<group id="ownership">
			<label>Rights</label>
			<help>your right to share this data with people</help>
			<question id="publisherRights">
				<label>Do you have the right to make this data open?</label>
				<radioset required="required">
					<option value="yes">
						<label>yes, you have the rights to open this data up</label>
						<requirement level="standard">You should have a <strong>clear legal right to publish this data</strong>.</requirement>
					</option>
					<option value="no">
						<label>no, you don’t have the rights to open up this data</label>
					</option>
					<option value="unsure">
						<label>you’re not sure if you have the rights to publish this data as open data</label>
					</option>
					<option value="complicated">
						<label>the rights in this data are complicated or unclear</label>
					</option>
				</radioset>
				<help>If your organisation did not originally create or gather this data then you may not have the right to publish it as open data. If you are not sure, please check with the data owner for their permission.
				<br/>
				Open data is data that anyone anyone can access, use and share – subject only, at most, to the requirement to attribute and share-alike – see our page explaining ‘<a href="https://theodi.org/what-is-open-data">what is open data?</a>’ and the <a href="http://opendefinition.org">open definition</a> for more details.</help>
				<if test="this.publisherRights() === 'no'">
					<requirement>You must have the <strong>right to publish this data</strong>.</requirement>
				</if>
			</question>
			<if test="this.publisherRights() === 'complicated'">
				<question id="rightsRiskAssessment" display="Risks in using this data are described at">
					<label>Where do you detail the risks people might encounter if they use this data?</label>
					<input type="url" placeholder="Risk Documentation URL"/>
					<help>It can be risky for people to use data without a clear legal right to do so. For example, the data might be taken down in response to a legal challenge. Give a URL for a page that describes the risk of using this data.</help>
					<requirement level="pilot">You should document <strong>risks associated with using this data</strong>, so people can work out how they want to use it.</requirement>
				</question>
			</if>
			<if test="this.publisherRights() === 'yes' || this.publisherRights() === 'unsure'">
				<question id="publisherOrigin" display="This data was">
					<label>Was the data originally created or generated by you?</label>
					<radioset>
						<option value="true" display="originally created or generated by its curator">
							<label>yes</label>
						</option>
						<option value="false" display="">
							<label>no, it uses external sources</label>
						</option>
					</radioset>
					<help>If any part of this data was sourced outside your organisation by other individuals or organisations then you need to give extra information about your right to publish it.</help>
				</question>
			</if>
			<if test="this.publisherRights() === 'unsure'">
				<if test="this.publisherOrigin() === 'false'">
					<question id="thirdPartyOrigin">
						<label>Was some of this data extracted or calculated from other data?</label>
						<yesno required="required"/>
						<help>An extract or smaller part of someone else's data still means your rights to use it might be affected. There might also be legal issues if you analysed their data to produce new results from it.</help>
						<if test="this.crowdsourced() === 'false'">
							<requirement test="this.thirdPartyOrigin() === 'true'">You indicated that this data wasn't originally created or gathered by you, and wasn't crowdsourced, so it must have been extracted or calculated from other data sources.</requirement>
						</if>
					</question>
					<if test="this.thirdPartyOrigin() === 'true'">
						<question id="thirdPartyOpen" display="This data is created from">
							<label>Are <em>all</em> sources of this data already published as open data?</label>
							<yesno required="required" yes="open data sources" />
							<help>You're allowed to republish someone else's data if it's already under an open data licence or if their rights have expired or been waived. If any part of this data is not like this then you'll need legal advice before you can publish it.</help>
							<if test="this.thirdPartyOpen() === 'false'">
								<requirement>You should get <strong>legal advice to make sure you have the right to publish this data</strong>.</requirement>
							</if>
						</question>
					</if>
					<question id="crowdsourced" display="Some of this data is">
						<label>Was some of this data crowdsourced?</label>
						<yesno required="required" yes="crowdsourced" />
						<help>If the data includes information contributed by people outside your organisation, you need their permission to publish their contributions as open data.</help>
						<if test="this.thirdPartyOrigin() === 'false'">
							<requirement test="this.crowdsourced() === 'true'">You indicated that the data wasn't originally created or gathered by you, and wasn't extracted or calculated from other data, so it must have been crowdsourced.</requirement>
						</if>
					</question>
					<if test="this.crowdsourced() === 'true'">
						<question id="crowdsourcedContent">
							<label>Did contributors to this data use their judgement?</label>
							<yesno required="required"/>
							<help>If people used their creativity or judgement to contribute data then they have copyright over their work. For example, writing a description or deciding whether or not to include some data in a dataset would require judgement. So contributors must transfer or waive their rights, or license the data to you before you can publish it.</help>
						</question>
						<if test="this.crowdsourcedContent() === 'true'">
							<question id="claUrl" display="The Contributor Licence Agreement is at">
								<label>Where is the Contributor Licence Agreement (CLA)?</label>
								<input type="url" placeholder="Contributor Licence Agreement URL" required="required"/>
								<help more="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Contributor_License_Agreement">Give a link to an agreement that shows contributors allow you to reuse their data. A CLA will either transfer contributor's rights to you, waive their rights, or license the data to you so you can publish it.</help>
							</question>
							<question id="cldsRecorded">
								<label>Have all contributors agreed to the Contributor Licence Agreement (CLA)?</label>
								<yesno required="required"/>
								<help>Check all contributors agree to a CLA before you reuse or republish their contributions. You should keep a record of who gave contributions and whether or not they agree to the CLA.</help>
								<requirement>You must get <strong>contributors to agree to a Contributor Licence Agreement</strong> (CLA) that gives you the right to publish their work as open data.</requirement>
							</question>
						</if>
					</if>
				</if>
			</if>
			<if test="this.publisherOrigin() === 'false'">
				<question id="sourceDocumentationUrl" display="The sources of this data are described at">
					<label>Where do you describe sources of this data?</label>
					<input type="url" placeholder="Data Sources Documentation URL"/>
					<help>Give a URL that documents where the data was sourced from (its provenance) and the rights under which you publish the data. This helps people understand where the data comes from.</help>
					<requirement level="pilot">You should document <strong>where the data came from and the rights under which you publish it</strong>, so people are assured they can use parts which came from third parties.</requirement>
				</question>
				<if test="this.sourceDocumentationUrl() !== ''">
					<question id="sourceDocumentationMetadata" display="The curator has published">
						<label>Is documentation about the sources of this data also in machine-readable format?</label>
						<yesno yes="machine-readable data about the sources of this data" />
						<help>Information about data sources should be human-readable so people can understand it, as well as in a metadata format that computers can process. When everyone does this it helps other people find out how the same open data is being used and justify its ongoing publication.</help>
						<requirement level="standard">You should <strong>include machine-readable data about the sources of this data</strong>.</requirement>
					</question>
				</if>
			</if>
		</group>
		<group id="licensing">
			<label>Licensing</label>
			<help>how you give people permission to use this data</help>
			<question id="copyrightURL" display="The rights statement is at">
				<label>Where have you published the rights statement for this dataset?</label>
				<input type="url" placeholder="Rights Statement URL"/>
				<help>Give the URL to a page that describes the right to re-use this dataset. This should include a reference to its license, attribution requirements, and a statement about relevant copyright and database rights. A rights statement helps people understand what they can and can't do with the data.</help>
				<requirement level="pilot">You should <strong>publish a rights statement</strong> that details copyright, database rights, licensing and how people should give attribution to the data.</requirement>
			</question>
            <!-- Czech-specific licensing questions follow -->
            <!-- Database Rights -->
            <question id="databaseRights" display="Database rights to the dataset">
               <label>Do database rights apply to your dataset?</label>
               <yesno yes="apply" no="not applicable"/>
               <help>In the Czech law system, each dataset can be considered from two viewpoints,
               as a database and as a creative work. In this question we consider the first case:
               each database that was creating using non-trivial effort is protected by database
               rights.</help>
            </question>
            <if test="this.databaseRights() === 'true'">
               <question id="databaseRightsLicenseType" display="Database rights licensing">
                   <label>How are the database rights to your dataset licensed?</label>
                   <option value="cc-by">Creative Commons 3.0 Attribution</option>
                   <option value="cc-by-sa">Creative Commons 3.0 Attribution-ShareAlike</option>
                   <option value="cc-by-4">Creative Commons 4.0 Attribution</option>
                   <option value="cc-by-sa-4">Creative Commons 4.0 Attribution-ShareAlike</option>
                   <option value="cc-zero">Creative Commons CC0</option>
                   <option value="odc-by">Open Data Commons Attribution License</option>
                   <option value="odc-odbl">Open Data Commons Open Database License (ODbL)</option>
                   <option value="odc-pddl">Open Data Commons Public Domain Dedication and License (PDDL)</option>
                   <option value="other" display="">other…</option>
                   <help>If you want to publish your dataset as open data, you must have an open license
                   to its database rights.</help>
               </question>
            </if>
            <if test="this.databaseRights() === 'other'">
               <question id="databaseRightsURL" display="Database rights license">
                  <label>Where do you describe the licensing terms for the database rights?</label>
                  <input type="url" required="required" placeholder="license URL"/>
               </question>
            </if>
            <if test="this.databaseRights() === 'false'">
               <question id="databaseRightsNAReason" display="Database rights do not apply because">
                   <display>Why there are no database rights to the dataset?</display>
                   <option value="trivial" display="creating the dataset was trivial">
                       Non-trivial effort wasn’t needed to create the dataset.</option>
                   <option value="expired" display="the rights expired">
                       The database rights expired.</option>
                   <option value="waived" display="the rights were waived">
                       The rights were waived by their holders.</option>
               </question>
            </if>
            <if test="this.databaseRightsNAReason() === 'waived'">
               <question id="databaseRightsWaiveType" display="The database rights were waived through">
                   <label>How were the database rights waived?</label>
                   <option value="cc-zero">Creative Commons CC0</option>
                   <option value="odc-pddl">Open Data Commons Public Domain Dedication and License (PDDL)</option>
                   <option value="other" display="">other…</option>
               </question>
            </if>
            <if test="this.databaseRightsWaiveType() === 'other'">
               <question id="databaseRightsWaiverURL" display="Database rights waiver">
                   <label>Where is the document used to waive the database rights?</label>
                  <input type="url" required="required" placeholder="waiver URL"/>
               </question>
            </if>
            <!-- Database Copyright -->
            <question id="databaseCopyright" display="Copyright to the dataset itself">
               <label>Does copyright apply to the dataset itself?</label>
               <yesno yes="applies" no="none"/>
               <help>The dataset can also be protected by copyright. There are two parts that can be
               copyrighted: the dataset itself and the contents of the dataset. This question is interested
               in the first case, the copyright protection of the dataset itself as a creative work.</help>
            </question>
            <if test="this.databaseCopyright() === 'false'">
               <question id="databaseCopyrightNAReason" display="The dataset itself is not copyrighted because">
                   <label>Why doesn’t copyright apply to the dataset itself?</label>
                   <option value="expired" display="the copyright has expired">
                       The copyright has expired.</option>
                   <option value="freeWork" display="the dataset is public domain">
                       The dataset is public domain.</option>
                   <option value="stateWork" display="the dataset is a government work">
                       The dataset is a government work.</option>
               </question>
            </if>
            <if test="this.databaseCopyright() === 'true'">
               <question id="databaseCopyrightLicenseType" display="Dataset copyright license">
                   <label>How is the copyright to the dataset itself licensed?</label>
                   <option value="cc-by">Creative Commons 3.0 Attribution</option>
                   <option value="cc-by-sa">Creative Commons 3.0 Attribution-ShareAlike</option>
                   <option value="cc-by-4">Creative Commons 4.0 Attribution</option>
                   <option value="cc-by-sa-4">Creative Commons 4.0 Attribution-ShareAlike</option>
                   <option value="cc-zero">Creative Commons CC0</option>
                   <option value="other" display="">other…</option>
                   <help>If you want to publish the dataset as open data, you must have
                   an open license to its copyright.</help>
               </question>
            </if>
            <if test="this.databaseCopyrightLicenseType() === 'other'">
               <question id="databaseCopyrightURL" display="Dataset copyright license">
                  <label>Where do you describe the dataset copyright licensing terms?</label>
                  <input type="url" required="required" placeholder="license URL"/>
               </question>
            </if>
            <!-- Database Content Copyright -->
            <question id="databaseContentCopyright" display="Dataset contents copyright">
               <label>Does copyright apply to the contents of your dataset?</label>
               <yesno yes="applies" no="none"/>
               <help>After the database rights and copyright to the dataset itself we are interested
               in the third kind of rights that may protect the dataset: copyright to the contents of
               your dataset.</help>
            </question>
            <if test="this.databaseContentCopyright() === 'false'">
               <question id="databaseContentCopyrightNAReason" display="The dataset contents are not copyrighted because">
                   <label>Why is there no copyright to the contents of your dataset?</label>
                   <option value="notApplicable" display="copyright does not apply to this kind of content">
                       Copyright does not apply to this kind of content.</option>
                   <option value="expired" display="the copyright has expired">
                       The copyright has expired.</option>
                   <option value="freeWork" display="the contents are public domain">
                       The dataset contents are public domain.</option>
                   <option value="stateWork" display="the contents are a government work">
                       The dataset contents are a government work.</option>
               </question>
            </if>
            <if test="this.databaseCopyright() === 'true'">
               <question id="databaseContentCopyrightLicenseType" display="Dataset contents copyright license">
                   <label>How is the copyright to the dataset contents licensed?</label>
                   <option value="cc-by">Creative Commons 3.0 Attribution</option>
                   <option value="cc-by-sa">Creative Commons 3.0 Attribution-ShareAlike</option>
                   <option value="cc-by-4">Creative Commons 4.0 Attribution</option>
                   <option value="cc-by-sa-4">Creative Commons 4.0 Attribution-ShareAlike</option>
                   <option value="cc-zero">Creative Commons CC0</option>
                   <option value="other" display="">other…</option>
               </question>
            </if>
            <if test="this.databaseContentCopyrightLicenseType() === 'other'">
               <question id="databaseContentCopyrightURL" display="Dataset contents copyright license">
                  <label>Where do you describe the licensing terms for the copyright to the dataset contents?</label>
                  <input type="url" required="required" placeholder="license URL"/>
               </question>
            </if>
            <!-- End of Czech-specific licensing questions -->
			<if test="this.copyrightURL() !== ''">
				<question id="copyrightStatementMetadata" display="The rights statement includes data about">
					<label>Does your rights statement include machine-readable versions of</label>
					<!-- these are properties from ODRS at https://github.com/theodi/open-data-licensing -->
					<checkboxset>
						<option value="dataLicense" display="its data licence">
							<label>data licence</label>
							<requirement level="standard">You should provide <strong>machine-readable data in your rights statement about the licence</strong> for this data, so automatic tools can use it.</requirement>
						</option>
						<option value="contentLicense" display="its content licence">
							<label>content licence</label>
							<requirement level="standard">You should provide <strong>machine-readable data in your rights statement about the licence for the content</strong> of this data, so automatic tools can use it.</requirement>
						</option>
						<option value="attribution" display="what attribution text to use">
							<label>attribution text</label>
							<requirement level="standard">You should provide <strong>machine-readable data in your rights statement about the text to use when citing the data</strong>, so automatic tools can use it.</requirement>
						</option>
						<option value="attributionURL" display="what attribution link to give">
							<label>attribution URL</label>
							<requirement level="standard">You should provide <strong>machine-readable data in your rights statement about the URL to link to when citing this data</strong>, so automatic tools can use it.</requirement>
						</option>
						<option value="copyrightNotice" display="a copyright notice or statement">
							<label>copyright notice or statement</label>
							<requirement level="exemplar">You should provide <strong>machine-readable data in your rights statement about the copyright statement or notice of this data</strong>, so automatic tools can use it.</requirement>
						</option>
						<option value="copyrightYear" display="the copyright year">
							<label>copyright year</label>
							<requirement level="exemplar">You should provide <strong>machine-readable data in your rights statement about the copyright year for the data</strong>, so automatic tools can use it.</requirement>
						</option>
						<option value="copyrightHolder" display="the copyright holder">
							<label>copyright holder</label>
							<requirement level="exemplar">You should provide <strong>machine-readable data in your rights statement about the copyright holder for the data</strong>, so automatic tools can use it.</requirement>
						</option>
						<option value="databaseRightYear" display="the database right year">
							<label>database right year</label>
							<requirement level="exemplar">You should provide <strong>machine-readable data in your rights statement about the database right year for the data</strong>, so automatic tools can use it.</requirement>
						</option>
						<option value="databaseRightHolder" display="the database right holder">
							<label>database right holder</label>
							<requirement level="exemplar">You should provide <strong>machine-readable data in your rights statement about the database right holder for the data</strong>, so automatic tools can use it.</requirement>
						</option>
					</checkboxset>
					<help more="https://github.com/theodi/open-data-licensing/blob/master/guides/publisher-guide.md">It's good practice to embed information about rights in machine-readable formats so people can automatically attribute this data back to you when they use it.</help>
				</question>
			</if>
		</group>
		<group id="privacy">
			<label>Privacy</label>
			<help>how you protect people's privacy</help>
			<question id="dataPersonal" display="This data contains">
				<label>Can individuals be identified from this data?</label>
				<radioset required="pilot">
					<option value="not-personal" display="no data about individuals">
						<label>no, the data is not about people or their activities</label>
						<help>Remember that individuals can still be identified even if data isn't directly about them. For example, road traffic flow data combined with an individual's commuting patterns could reveal information about that person.</help>
					</option>
					<option value="summarised" display="aggregated data">
						<label>no, the data has been anonymised by aggregating individuals into groups, so they can't be distinguished from other people in the group</label>
						<help more="http://www.ons.gov.uk/ons/guide-method/best-practice/disclosure-control-policy-for-tables/index.html">Statistical disclosure controls can help to make sure that individuals are not identifiable within aggregate data.</help>
					</option>
					<option value="individual" display="information that could identify individuals">
						<label>yes, there is a risk that individuals be identified, for example by third parties with access to extra information</label>
						<help>Some data is legitimately about individuals like civil service pay or public expenses for example.</help>
					</option>
				</radioset>
			</question>
			<if test="this.dataPersonal() === 'summarised'">
				<question id="statisticalAnonAudited" display="The anonymisation process has been">
					<label>Has your anonymisation process been independently audited?</label>
					<yesno yes="independently audited" />
					<requirement level="standard">You should <strong>have your anonymisation process audited independently</strong> to ensure it reduces the risk of individuals being reidentified.</requirement>
				</question>
			</if>
			<if test="this.dataPersonal() === 'individual'">
				<question id="appliedAnon" display="This data about individuals has been">
					<label>Have you attempted to reduce or remove the possibility of individuals being identified?</label>
					<yesno required="pilot" yes="anonymised" />
					<help>Anonymisation reduces the risk of individuals being identified from the data you publish. The best technique to use depends on the kind of data you have.</help>
				</question>
				<if test="this.appliedAnon() === 'false'">
					<question id="lawfulDisclosure" display="By law, this data about individuals">
						<label>Are you required or permitted by law to publish this data about individuals?</label>
						<yesno yes="can be published" />
						<help>The law might require you to publish data about people, such as the names of company directors. Or you might have permission from the affected individuals to publish information about them.</help>
						<requirement level="pilot">You should <strong>only publish personal data without anonymisation if you are required or permitted to do so by law</strong>.</requirement>
					</question>
					<if test="this.lawfulDisclosure() === 'true'">
						<question id="lawfulDisclosureURL" display="The right to publish this data about individuals is documented at">
							<label>Where do you document your right to publish data about individuals?</label>
							<input type="url" placeholder="Disclosure Rationale URL"/>
							<requirement level="standard">You should <strong>document your right to publish data about individuals</strong> for people who use your data and for those affected by disclosure.</requirement>
						</question>
					</if>
				</if>
				<if test="this.appliedAnon() === 'true' || this.lawfulDisclosure() === 'true'">
					<question id="privacyImpactAssessmentExists" display="The curator has">
						<label>Have you carried out a Privacy Impact Assessment?</label>
						<yesno yes="carried out a Privacy Impact Assessment" no="not carried out a Privacy Impact Assessment" />
						<help more="http://www.ico.gov.uk/for_organisations/data_protection/topic_guides/privacy_impact_assessment.aspx">A <a href="http://www.ico.gov.uk/for_organisations/data_protection/topic_guides/privacy_impact_assessment.aspx">Privacy Impact Assessment</a> is how you measure risks to the privacy of individuals in your data as well as the use and disclosure of that information.</help>
						<requirement level="pilot">You should <strong>do a Privacy Impact Assessment</strong> if you publish data about individuals.</requirement>
					</question>
					<if test="this.privacyImpactAssessmentExists() === 'true'">
						<question id="privacyImpactAssessmentUrl" display="The Privacy Impact Assessment is published at">
							<label>Where is your Privacy Impact Assessment published?</label>
							<input type="url" placeholder="Privacy Impact Assessment URL"/>
							<help more="http://www.ico.gov.uk/for_organisations/data_protection/topic_guides/privacy_impact_assessment.aspx">Give a URL to where people can check how you have assessed the privacy risks to individuals. This may be redacted or summarised if it contains sensitive information.</help>
							<requirement level="standard">You should <strong>publish your Privacy Impact Assessment</strong> so people can understand how you have assessed the risks of disclosing data.</requirement>
						</question>
						<if test="this.privacyImpactAssessmentUrl() !== ''">
							<question id="piaAudited" display="The Privacy Impact Assessment has been">
								<label>Has your Privacy Impact Assessment been independently audited?</label>
								<yesno yes="independently audited" />
								<help>It's good practice to check your assessment was done correctly. Independent audits by specialists or third-parties tend to be more rigorous and impartial.</help>
								<requirement level="standard">You should <strong>have your Privacy Impact Assessment audited independently</strong> to ensure it has been carried out correctly.</requirement>
							</question>
						</if>
						<if test="this.lawfulDisclosure() !== 'true'">
							<question id="individualConsentURL" display="Individuals affected by this data have this privacy notice">
								<label>Where is the privacy notice for individuals affected by your data?</label>
								<input type="url" placeholder="Privacy Notice URL"/>
								<help more="http://www.ico.org.uk/for_organisations/data_protection/the_guide/principle_2">When you collect data about individuals you must tell them how that data will be used. People who use your data need this to make sure they comply with the Data Protection Act.</help>
								<requirement level="pilot">You should <strong>tell people what purposes the individuals in your data consented to you using their data for</strong>. So that they use your data for the same purposes and comply with the Data Protection Act.</requirement>
							</question>
						</if>
						<question id="dpStaff">
							<label>Is there someone in your organisation who is responsible for data protection?</label>
							<yesno required="pilot"/>
						</question>
						<if test="this.dpStaff() === 'true'">
							<question id="dbStaffConsulted" display="The individual responsible for data protection">
								<label>Have you involved them in the Privacy Impact Assessment process?</label>
								<yesno yes="has been consulted" />
								<requirement level="pilot">You should <strong>involve the person responsible for data protection</strong> in your organisation before you publish this data.</requirement>
							</question>
						</if>
						<question id="anonymisationAudited" display="The anonymisation of the data has been">
							<label>Has your anonymisation approach been independently audited?</label>
							<yesno yes="independently audited" />
							<help>It is good practice to make sure your process to remove personal identifiable data works properly. Independent audits by specialists or third-parties tend to be more rigorous and impartial.</help>
							<requirement level="standard">You should <strong>have your anonymisation process audited independently</strong> by an expert to ensure it is appropriate for your data.</requirement>
						</question>
					</if>
				</if>
			</if>
		</group>
	</group>
</questionnaire>
