<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!--
	© 2013 Open Data Institute
	This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 2.0 UK: England & Wales License.
	http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/2.0/uk/deed.en_GB
  --><?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../surveyor.xsl"?><questionnaire version="0.9" status="alpha" jurisdiction="TW" xml:lang="en">
	<help><p><strong>This has been generated based on a default and needs to be localised for Taiwan. Please help us! Contact <a href="mailto:certificate@theodi.org">certificate@theodi.org</a></strong></p>
		<p>This self-assessment questionnaire generates an open data certificate and badge you can publish to tell people all about this open data. We also use your answers to learn how organisations publish open data.</p>
		<p>When you answer these questions it demonstrates your efforts to comply with relevant legislation. You should also check which other laws and policies apply to your sector.</p>
		<p><strong>You do not need to answer all the questions to get a certificate.</strong> Just answer those you can.</p>
	</help>
	<group id="legal">
		<label>Legal Information</label>
		<help>Rights, licensing and privacy</help>
		<group id="ownership">
			<label>Rights</label>
			<help>your right to share this data with people</help>
			<question id="publisherRights">
				<label>Do you have the rights to publish this data as open data?</label>
				<radioset required="required">
					<option value="yes">
						<label>yes, you have the rights to publish this data as open data</label>
						<requirement level="standard">You should have a <strong>clear legal right to publish this data</strong>.</requirement>
					</option>
					<option value="no">
						<label>no, you don't have the rights to publish this data as open data</label>
					</option>
					<option value="unsure">
						<label>you're not sure if you have the rights to publish this data as open data</label>
					</option>
					<option value="complicated">
						<label>the rights in this data are complicated or unclear</label>
					</option>
				</radioset>
				<help>If your organisation didn't originally create or gather this data then you might not have the right to publish it. If you’re not sure, check with the data owner because you will need their permission to publish it.</help>
				<if test="this.publisherRights() === 'no'">
					<requirement>You must have the <strong>right to publish this data</strong>.</requirement>
				</if>
			</question>
			<if test="this.publisherRights() === 'complicated'">
				<question id="rightsRiskAssessment" display="Risks in using this data are described at">
					<label>Where do you detail the risks people might encounter if they use this data?</label>
					<input type="url" placeholder="Risk Documentation URL"/>
					<help>It can be risky for people to use data without a clear legal right to do so. For example, the data might be taken down in response to a legal challenge. Give a URL for a page that describes the risk of using this data.</help>
					<requirement level="pilot">You should document <strong>risks associated with using this data</strong>, so people can work out how they want to use it.</requirement>
				</question>
			</if>
			<if test="this.publisherRights() === 'yes' || this.publisherRights() === 'unsure'">
				<question id="publisherOrigin" display="This data was">
					<label>Was <em>all</em> this data originally created or gathered by you?</label>
					<yesno required="required" yes="originally created or generated by its curator"/>
					<help>If any part of this data was sourced outside your organisation by other individuals or organisations then you need to give extra information about your right to publish it.</help>
				</question>
			</if>
			<if test="this.publisherRights() === 'unsure'">
				<if test="this.publisherOrigin() === 'false'">
					<question id="thirdPartyOrigin">
						<label>Was some of this data extracted or calculated from other data?</label>
						<yesno required="required"/>
						<help>An extract or smaller part of someone else's data still means your rights to use it might be affected. There might also be legal issues if you analysed their data to produce new results from it.</help>
						<if test="this.crowdsourced() === 'false'">
							<requirement test="this.thirdPartyOrigin() === 'true'">You indicated that this data wasn't originally created or gathered by you, and wasn't crowdsourced, so it must have been extracted or calculated from other data sources.</requirement>
						</if>
					</question>
					<if test="this.thirdPartyOrigin() === 'true'">
						<question id="thirdPartyOpen" display="This data is created from">
							<label>Are <em>all</em> sources of this data already published as open data?</label>
							<yesno required="required" yes="open data sources"/>
							<help>You're allowed to republish someone else's data if it's already under an open data licence or if their rights have expired or been waived. If any part of this data is not like this then you'll need legal advice before you can publish it.</help>
							<if test="this.thirdPartyOpen() === 'false'">
								<requirement>You should get <strong>legal advice to make sure you have the right to publish this data</strong>.</requirement>
							</if>
						</question>
					</if>
					<question id="crowdsourced" display="Some of this data is">
						<label>Was some of this data crowdsourced?</label>
						<yesno required="required" yes="crowdsourced"/>
						<help>If the data includes information contributed by people outside your organisation, you need their permission to publish their contributions as open data.</help>
						<if test="this.thirdPartyOrigin() === 'false'">
							<requirement test="this.crowdsourced() === 'true'">You indicated that the data wasn't originally created or gathered by you, and wasn't extracted or calculated from other data, so it must have been crowdsourced.</requirement>
						</if>
					</question>
					<if test="this.crowdsourced() === 'true'">
						<question id="crowdsourcedContent">
							<label>Did contributors to this data use their judgement?</label>
							<yesno required="required"/>
							<help>If people used their creativity or judgement to contribute data then they have copyright over their work. For example, writing a description or deciding whether or not to include some data in a dataset would require judgement. So contributors must transfer or waive their rights, or license the data to you before you can publish it.</help>
						</question>
						<if test="this.crowdsourcedContent() === 'true'">
							<question id="claUrl" display="The Contributor Licence Agreement is at">
								<label>Where is the Contributor Licence Agreement (CLA)?</label>
								<input type="url" placeholder="Contributor Licence Agreement URL" required="required"/>
								<help more="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Contributor_License_Agreement">Give a link to an agreement that shows contributors allow you to reuse their data. A CLA will either transfer contributor's rights to you, waive their rights, or license the data to you so you can publish it.</help>
							</question>
							<question id="cldsRecorded">
								<label>Have all contributors agreed to the Contributor Licence Agreement (CLA)?</label>
								<yesno required="required"/>
								<help>Check all contributors agree to a CLA before you reuse or republish their contributions. You should keep a record of who gave contributions and whether or not they agree to the CLA.</help>
								<requirement>You must get <strong>contributors to agree to a Contributor Licence Agreement</strong> (CLA) that gives you the right to publish their work as open data.</requirement>
							</question>
						</if>
					</if>
				</if>
			</if>
			<if test="this.publisherOrigin() === 'false'">
				<question id="sourceDocumentationUrl" display="The sources of this data are described at">
					<label>Where do you describe sources of this data?</label>
					<input type="url" placeholder="Data Sources Documentation URL"/>
					<help>Give a URL that documents where the data was sourced from (its provenance) and the rights under which you publish the data. This helps people understand where the data comes from.</help>
					<requirement level="pilot">You should document <strong>where the data came from and the rights under which you publish it</strong>, so people are assured they can use parts which came from third parties.</requirement>
				</question>
				<if test="this.sourceDocumentationUrl() !== ''">
					<question id="sourceDocumentationMetadata" display="The curator has published">
						<label>Is documentation about the sources of this data also in machine-readable format?</label>
						<yesno yes="machine-readable data about the sources of this data"/>
						<help>Information about data sources should be human-readable so people can understand it, as well as in a metadata format that computers can process. When everyone does this it helps other people find out how the same open data is being used and justify its ongoing publication.</help>
						<requirement level="standard">You should <strong>include machine-readable data about the sources of this data</strong>.</requirement>
					</question>
				</if>
			</if>
		</group>
		<group id="licensing">
			<label>Licensing</label>
			<help>how you give people permission to use this data</help>
			<question id="copyrightURL" display="The rights statement is at">
				<label>Where have you published the rights statement for this dataset?</label>
				<input type="url" placeholder="Rights Statement URL"/>
				<help>Give the URL to a page that describes the right to re-use this dataset. This should include a reference to its license, attribution requirements, and a statement about relevant copyright. A rights statement helps people understand what they can and can't do with the data.</help>
				<requirement level="pilot">You should <strong>publish a rights statement</strong> that details copyright, licensing and how people should give attribution to the data.</requirement>
			</question>
			<question id="dataLicence" display="This data is available under">
				<label>Under which licence can people reuse this data?</label>
				<select required="required">
					<option/>
					<option value="odc-by">Open Data Commons Attribution License</option>
					<option value="odc-odbl">Open Data Commons Open Database License (ODbL)</option>
					<option value="odc-pddl">Open Data Commons Public Domain Dedication and Licence (PDDL)</option>
					<option value="cc-zero">Creative Commons CCZero</option>
					<option value="na" display="">Not applicable</option>
					<option value="other" display="">Other...</option>
				</select>
				<help>Remember that whoever spends intellectual effort creating content automatically gets rights over it. Creative content includes the organisation and selection of items within data, but does not include facts. So people need a waiver or a licence which proves that they can use the data and explains how they can do that legally. We list the most common licenses here; if there is no copyright in the data, it's expired, or you've waived them, choose 'Not applicable'.</help>
			</question>
			<if test="this.dataLicence() === 'na'">
				<question id="dataNotApplicable" display="This data is not licensed because">
					<label>Why doesn't a licence apply to this data?</label>
					<radioset required="required">
						<option value="norights" display="there is no copyright in it">
							<label>there is no copyright in this data</label>
							<help>Copyright only applies to data if you spent intellectual effort creating what's in it, for example, by writing text that's within the data, or deciding whether particular data is included. There's no copyright if the data only contains facts where no judgements were made about whether to include them or not.</help>
						</option>
						<option value="expired" display="copyright has expired">
							<label>copyright has expired</label>
							<help>Copyright lasts for a fixed amount of time, based on either the number of years after the death of its creator or its publication. You should check when the content was created or published because if that was a long time ago, copyright might have expired.</help>
						</option>
						<option value="waived" display="">
							<label>copyright has been waived</label>
							<help>This means no one owns copyright and anyone can do whatever they want with this data.</help>
						</option>
					</radioset>
				</question>
				<if test="this.dataNotApplicable() === 'waived'">
					<question id="dataWaiver" display="Rights in the data have been waived with">
						<label>Which waiver do you use to waive copyright in the data?</label>
						<select required="required">
							<option/>
							<option value="pddl">Open Data Commons Public Domain Dedication and Licence (PDDL)</option>
							<option value="cc0">Creative Commons CCZero</option>
							<option value="other" display="">Other...</option>
						</select>
						<help>You need a statement to show people copyright has been waived, so they understand that they can do whatever they like with this data. Standard waivers already exist like PDDL and CCZero but you can write your own with legal advice.</help>
					</question>
					<if test="this.dataWaiver() === 'other'">
						<question id="dataOtherWaiver" display="Rights in the data have been waived with">
							<label>Where is the waiver for the copyright in the data?</label>
							<input type="url" required="required" placeholder="Waiver URL"/>
							<help>Give a URL to your own publicly available waiver so people can check that it does waive copyright in the data.</help>
						</question>
					</if>
				</if>
			</if>
			<if test="this.dataLicence() === 'other'">
				<question id="otherDataLicenceName" display="This data is available under">
					<label>What is the name of the licence?</label>
					<input required="required" placeholder="Other Licence Name"/>
					<help>If you use a different licence, we need the name so people can see it on your Open Data Certificate.</help>
				</question>
				<question id="otherDataLicenceURL" display="This licence is at">
					<label>Where is the licence?</label>
					<input type="url" required="required" placeholder="Other Licence URL"/>
					<help>Give a URL to the licence, so people can see it on your Open Data Certificate and check that it's publicly available.</help>
				</question>
				<question id="otherDataLicenceOpen">
					<label>Is the licence an open licence?</label>
					<yesno required="required"/>
					<help more="http://opendefinition.org/">If you aren't sure what an open licence is then read the <a href="http://opendefinition.org/">Open Knowledge Definition</a> definition. Next, choose your licence from the <a href="http://licenses.opendefinition.org/">Open Definition Advisory Board open licence list</a>. If a licence isn't in their list, it's either not open or hasn't been assessed yet.</help>
					<requirement>You must <strong>publish open data under an open licence</strong> so that people can use it.</requirement>
				</question>
			</if>
			<question id="contentRights" display="There are">
				<label>Is there any copyright in the content of this data?</label>
				<radioset required="required">
					<option value="norights" display="no rights in the content of the data">
						<label>no, the data only contains facts and numbers</label>
						<help>There is no copyright in factual information. If the data does not contain any content that was created through intellectual effort, there are no rights in the content.</help>
					</option>
					<option value="samerights" display="">
						<label>yes, and the rights are all held by the same person or organisation</label>
						<help>Choose this option if the content in the data was all created by or transferred to the same person or organisation.</help>
					</option>
					<option value="mixedrights" display="">
						<label>yes, and the rights are held by different people or organisations</label>
						<help>In some data, the rights in different records are held by different people or organisations. Information about rights needs to be kept in the data too.</help>
					</option>
				</radioset>
			</question>
			<if test="this.contentRights() === 'norights'">
				<question id="explicitWaiver" display="The content has been">
					<label>Is the content of the data marked as public domain?</label>
					<yesno yes="marked as public domain"/>
					<help>Content can be marked as public domain using the <a href="http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/">Creative Commons Public Domain Mark</a>. This helps people know that it can be freely reused.</help>
					<requirement level="standard">You should <strong>mark public domain content as public domain</strong> so that people know they can reuse it.</requirement>
				</question>
			</if>
			<if test="this.contentRights() === 'samerights'">
				<question id="contentLicence" display="The content is available under">
					<label>Under which licence can others reuse content?</label>
					<select required="required">
						<option/>
						<option value="cc-by">Creative Commons Attribution</option>
						<option value="cc-by-sa">Creative Commons Attribution Share-Alike</option>
						<option value="cc-zero">Creative Commons CCZero</option>
						<option value="na" display="">Not applicable</option>
						<option value="other" display="">Other...</option>
					</select>
					<help>Remember that whoever spends intellectual effort creating content automatically gets rights over it but creative content does not include facts. So people need a waiver or a licence which proves that they can use the content and explains how they can do that legally. We list the most common licenses here; if there is no copyright in the content, it's expired, or you've waived them, choose 'Not applicable'.</help>
				</question>
				<if test="this.contentLicence() === 'na'">
					<question id="contentNotApplicable" display="The content in this data is not licensed because">
						<label>Why doesn't a licence apply to the content of the data?</label>
						<radioset required="required">
							<option value="norights" display="there is no copyright">
								<label>there is no copyright in the content of this data</label>
								<help>Copyright only applies to content if you spent intellectual effort creating it, for example, by writing text that's within the data. There's no copyright if the content only contains facts.</help>
							</option>
							<option value="expired" display="copyright has expired">
								<label>copyright has expired</label>
								<help>Copyright lasts for a fixed amount of time, based on either the number of years after the death of its creator or its publication. You should check when the content was created or published because if that was a long time ago, copyright might have expired.</help>
							</option>
							<option value="waived" display="">
								<label>copyright has been waived</label>
								<help>This means no one owns copyright and anyone can do whatever they want with this data.</help>
							</option>
						</radioset>
					</question>
					<if test="this.contentNotApplicable() === 'waived'">
						<question id="contentWaiver" display="Copyright has been waived with">
							<label>Which waiver do you use to waive copyright?</label>
							<select required="required">
								<option/>
								<option value="cc0">Creative Commons CCZero</option>
								<option value="other">Other...</option>
							</select>
							<help>You need a statement to show people you've done this, so they understand that they can do whatever they like with this data. Standard waivers already exist like CCZero but you can write your own with legal advice.</help>
						</question>
						<if test="this.contentWaiver() === 'other'">
							<question id="contentOtherWaiver" display="Copyright has been waived with">
								<label>Where is the waiver for the copyright?</label>
								<input type="url" required="required" placeholder="Waiver URL"/>
								<help>Give a URL to your own publicly available waiver so people can check that it does waive your copyright.</help>
							</question>
						</if>
					</if>
				</if>
				<if test="this.contentLicence() === 'other'">
					<question id="otherContentLicenceName" display="The content is available under">
						<label>What's the name of the licence?</label>
						<input required="required" placeholder="Licence Name"/>
						<help>If you use a different licence, we need its name so people can see it on your Open Data Certificate.</help>
					</question>
					<question id="otherContentLicenceURL" display="The content licence is at">
						<label>Where is the licence?</label>
						<input type="url" required="required" placeholder="Licence URL"/>
						<help>Give a URL to the licence, so people can see it on your Open Data Certificate and check that it's publicly available.</help>
					</question>
					<question id="otherContentLicenceOpen">
						<label>Is the licence an open licence?</label>
						<yesno required="required"/>
						<help more="http://opendefinition.org/">If you aren't sure what an open licence is then read the <a href="http://opendefinition.org/">Open Knowledge Definition</a> definition. Next, choose your licence from the <a href="http://licenses.opendefinition.org/">Open Definition Advisory Board open licence list</a>. If a licence isn't in their list, it's either not open or hasn't been assessed yet.</help>
						<requirement>You must <strong>publish open data under an open licence</strong> so that people can use it.</requirement>
					</question>
				</if>
			</if>
			<if test="this.contentRights() === 'mixedrights'">
				<question id="contentRightsURL" display="The rights and licensing of the content are explained at">
					<label>Where are the rights and licensing of the content explained?</label>
					<input type="url" required="required" placeholder="Content Rights Description URL"/>
					<help>Give the URL for a page where you describe how someone can find out the rights and licensing of a piece of content from the data.</help>
				</question>
			</if>
			<if test="this.copyrightURL() !== ''">
				<question id="copyrightStatementMetadata" display="The rights statement includes data about">
					<label>Does your rights statement include machine-readable versions of</label>
					<!-- these are properties from ODRS at https://github.com/theodi/open-data-licensing -->
					<checkboxset>
						<option value="dataLicense" display="its data licence">
							<label>data licence</label>
							<requirement level="standard">You should provide <strong>machine-readable data in your rights statement about the licence</strong> for this data, so automatic tools can use it.</requirement>
						</option>
						<option value="contentLicense" display="its content licence">
							<label>content licence</label>
							<requirement level="standard">You should provide <strong>machine-readable data in your rights statement about the licence for the content</strong> of this data, so automatic tools can use it.</requirement>
						</option>
						<option value="attribution" display="what attribution text to use">
							<label>attribution text</label>
							<requirement level="standard">You should provide <strong>machine-readable data in your rights statement about the text to use when citing the data</strong>, so automatic tools can use it.</requirement>
						</option>
						<option value="attributionURL" display="what attribution link to give">
							<label>attribution URL</label>
							<requirement level="standard">You should provide <strong>machine-readable data in your rights statement about the URL to link to when citing this data</strong>, so automatic tools can use it.</requirement>
						</option>
						<option value="copyrightNotice" display="a copyright notice or statement">
							<label>copyright notice or statement</label>
							<requirement level="exemplar">You should provide <strong>machine-readable data in your rights statement about the copyright statement or notice of this data</strong>, so automatic tools can use it.</requirement>
						</option>
						<option value="copyrightYear" display="the copyright year">
							<label>copyright year</label>
							<requirement level="exemplar">You should provide <strong>machine-readable data in your rights statement about the copyright year for the data</strong>, so automatic tools can use it.</requirement>
						</option>
						<option value="copyrightHolder" display="the copyright holder">
							<label>copyright holder</label>
							<requirement level="exemplar">You should provide <strong>machine-readable data in your rights statement about the copyright holder for the data</strong>, so automatic tools can use it.</requirement>
						</option>
					</checkboxset>
					<help more="https://github.com/theodi/open-data-licensing/blob/master/guides/publisher-guide.md">It's good practice to embed information about rights in machine-readable formats so people can automatically attribute this data back to you when they use it.</help>
				</question>
			</if>
		</group>
		<group id="privacy">
			<label>Privacy</label>
			<help>how you protect people's privacy</help>
			<question id="dataPersonal" display="This data contains">
				<label>Can individuals be identified from this data?</label>
				<radioset required="pilot">
					<option value="not-personal" display="no data about individuals">
						<label>no, the data is not about people or their activities</label>
						<help>Remember that individuals can still be identified even if data isn't directly about them. For example, road traffic flow data combined with an individual's commuting patterns could reveal information about that person.</help>
					</option>
					<option value="summarised" display="aggregated data">
						<label>no, the data has been anonymised by aggregating individuals into groups, so they can't be distinguished from other people in the group</label>
						<help>Statistical disclosure controls can help to make sure that individuals are not identifiable within aggregate data.</help>
					</option>
					<option value="individual" display="information that could identify individuals">
						<label>yes, there is a risk that individuals be identified, for example by third parties with access to extra information</label>
						<help>Some data is legitimately about individuals like civil service pay or public expenses for example.</help>
					</option>
				</radioset>
			</question>
			<if test="this.dataPersonal() === 'summarised'">
				<question id="statisticalAnonAudited" display="The anonymisation process has been">
					<label>Has your anonymisation process been independently audited?</label>
					<yesno yes="independently audited"/>
					<requirement level="standard">You should <strong>have your anonymisation process audited independently</strong> to ensure it reduces the risk of individuals being reidentified.</requirement>
				</question>
			</if>
			<if test="this.dataPersonal() === 'individual'">
				<question id="appliedAnon" display="This data about individuals has been">
					<label>Have you attempted to reduce or remove the possibility of individuals being identified?</label>
					<yesno required="pilot" yes="anonymised"/>
					<help>Anonymisation reduces the risk of individuals being identified from the data you publish. The best technique to use depends on the kind of data you have.</help>
				</question>
				<if test="this.appliedAnon() === 'false'">
					<question id="lawfulDisclosure" display="By law, this data about individuals">
						<label>Are you required or permitted by law to publish this data about individuals?</label>
						<yesno yes="must be published"/>
						<requirement level="pilot">You should <strong>only publish personal data without anonymisation if you are required or permitted to do so by law</strong>.</requirement>
					</question>
					<if test="this.lawfulDisclosure() === 'true'">
						<question id="lawfulDisclosureURL" display="The right to publish this data about individuals is documented at">
							<label>Where do you document your right to publish data about individuals?</label>
							<input type="url" placeholder="Disclosure Rationale URL"/>
							<requirement level="standard">You should <strong>document your right to publish data about individuals</strong> for people who use your data and for those affected by disclosure.</requirement>
						</question>
					</if>
				</if>
				<if test="this.appliedAnon() === 'true' || this.lawfulDisclosure() === 'true'">
					<question id="riskAssessmentExists" display="The curator has">
						<label>Have you assessed the risks of disclosing personal data?</label>
						<yesno yes="carried out a privacy risk assessment" no="not carried out a privacy risk assessment"/>
						<help>A risk assessment measures risks to the privacy of individuals in your data as well as the use and disclosure of that information.</help>
						<requirement level="pilot">You should <strong>assess the risks of disclosing personal data</strong> if you publish data about individuals.</requirement>
					</question>
					<if test="this.riskAssessmentExists() === 'true'">
						<question id="riskAssessmentUrl" display="The risk assessment is published at">
							<label>Where is your risk assessment published?</label>
							<input type="url" placeholder="Risk Assessment URL"/>
							<help>Give a URL to where people can check how you have assessed the privacy risks to individuals. This may be redacted or summarised if it contains sensitive information.</help>
							<requirement level="standard">You should <strong>publish your privacy risk assessment</strong> so people can understand how you have assessed the risks of disclosing data.</requirement>
						</question>
						<if test="this.riskAssessmentUrl() !== ''">
							<question id="riskAssessmentAudited" display="The risk assessment has been">
								<label>Has your risk assessment been independently audited?</label>
								<yesno yes="independently audited"/>
								<help>It's good practice to check your risk assessment was done correctly. Independent audits by specialists or third-parties tend to be more rigorous and impartial.</help>
								<requirement level="standard">You should <strong>have your risk assessment audited independently</strong> to ensure it has been carried out correctly.</requirement>
							</question>
						</if>
						<question id="anonymisationAudited" display="The anonymisation of the data has been">
							<label>Has your anonymisation approach been independently audited?</label>
							<yesno yes="independently audited"/>
							<help>It is good practice to make sure your process to remove personal identifiable data works properly. Independent audits by specialists or third-parties tend to be more rigorous and impartial.</help>
							<requirement level="standard">You should <strong>have your anonymisation process audited independently</strong> by an expert to ensure it is appropriate for your data.</requirement>
						</question>
					</if>
				</if>
			</if>
		</group>
	</group>
</questionnaire>