<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!--
	© 2013 Open Data Institute
	This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 2.0 UK: England & Wales License.
	http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/2.0/uk/deed.en_GB
  -->
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="surveyor.xsl"?>
<questionnaire version="0.5" jurisdiction="UK">
	<levels>
		<level id="basic">This data satisfies the fundamental requirements for open data.</level>
		<level id="pilot">This data satisfies the requirements for initial forays into publishing open data. It provides sufficient support to prompt some reuser experimentation with a data.</level>
		<level id="standard">This data satisfies the requirements for routinely published open data that encourages reuse.</level>
		<level id="exemplar">This data satisfies the requirements for key information infrastructure.</level>
	</levels>
	<question id="dataTitle">
		<label>What's a good title for this data?</label>
		<input placeholder="Data Title" required="required"/>
		<help>This is the title that we will give to the open data within the Open Data Certificate. It will probably be the same as what you call the data elsewhere, but you should aim to be unambiguous, and consider the fact that there might be certificates for lots of similar open data.</help>
	</question>
	<!-- ask this first, because if a URL is given we can then go off and locate more information about the dataset -->
	<question id="documentationUrl">
		<label>Where is the data described?</label>
		<input type="url" placeholder="Documentation URL"/>
		<help>This should be the URL of a page that describes the open data and what it contains. This might be a page that describes the dataset within a catalog such as data.gov.uk. We ask for this page because it's useful for reusers to know about it, and because if it's written well then we can fill in a lot of things in this questionnaire based on the information within that page.</help>
		<if test="this.releaseType() !== 'collection'">
			<requirement level="pilot">You should have a page that provides documentation about the open data you are publishing so that reusers can understand its context, content and utility.</requirement>
		</if>
		<if test="this.releaseType() === 'collection'">
			<requirement test="this.documentationUrl() !== ''">You must have a page that provides documentation and access to the open data you are publishing so that reusers can get hold of it.</requirement>
		</if>
	</question>
	<question id="publisher">
		<label>What's the name of the curating organisation?</label>
		<input placeholder="Data Curator" required="required"/>
		<help>This is the organisation that the open data will be associated with the Open Data Certificate. It should be the organisation that manages the creation of and curates the open data. The data might actually be published by someone else, such as central government or a third-party contractor.</help>
	</question>
	<question id="publisherUrl">
		<label>What's the website for the curating organisation?</label>
		<input type="url" placeholder="Curator URL"/>
		<help>This should be the main website for your organisation or group. We use this to provide a link through to your organisation and to help us gather together all the open data curated by your organisation even if different people spell your organisation's name differently.</help>
	</question>
	<question id="releaseType">
		<label>What kind of data release is this?</label>
		<radioset required="required">
			<option value="oneoff">
				<label>a one-off release of a single dataset</label>
				<help>Choose this option if the open data release is the publication of a single file, such as a spreadsheet, with no intention to publish similar files in the future.</help>
			</option>
			<option value="collection">
				<label>a one-off release of a set of related datasets</label>
				<help>Choose this option if the open data release is the publication of a collection of related files, such as several spreadsheets created from the same underlying data, with no intention to publish similar collections in the future.</help>
			</option>
			<option value="series">
				<label>ongoing release of a series of related datasets</label>
				<help>Choose this open if you are releasing a series of datasets on a regular schedule, such as releasing a particular dataset every month.</help>
			</option>
			<option value="service">
				<label>a service or API for accessing open data</label>
				<help>Choose this option if you are providing an API or a web service. This option includes linked data publications where underlying data is exposed through a website.</help>
			</option>
		</radioset>
	</question>
	<group id="legal">
		<label>Legal Information</label>
		<group id="ownership">
			<label>Rights</label>
			<help>ensuring that you have the right to publish the data</help>
			<question id="publisherRights">
				<label>Do you have the rights to publish the data as open data?</label>
				<radioset required="required">
					<option value="yes">
						<label>yes, you have the right to publish the data as open data</label>
					</option>
					<option value="no">
						<label>no, you don't have the right to publish the data as open data</label>
					</option>
					<option value="unsure">
						<label>you don't know whether you have the right to publish the data as open data</label>
					</option>
				</radioset>
				<help>Unless all the data was originally created or gathered by your organisation, you might not have the right to republish it. We ask this question to check that you have considered the ownership of the data. If you aren't sure, we will ask further questions about the source of the data you're publishing to find out.</help>
				<if test="this.publisherRights() === 'no'">
					<requirement>You must have the right to publish data that you publish.</requirement>
				</if>
			</question>
			<if test="this.publisherRights() === 'yes' || this.publisherRights() === 'unsure'">
				<question id="publisherOrigin">
					<label>Was <em>all</em> this data originally created or gathered by you?</label>
					<yesno required="required" />
					<help>If not all the data was originally created or gathered by you then you might not have the right to republish it. Answer 'no' to this question if the data includes information that was sourced from outside your organisation, or if it includes data that other individuals or organisations have contributed. We ask this question to work out whether we have to ask about other organisations or people who might own some of the data.</help>
				</question>
			</if>
			<if test="this.publisherRights() === 'unsure'">
				<if test="this.publisherOrigin() === 'false'">
					<question id="thirdPartyOrigin">
						<label>Was some of this data extracted or calculated from other data?</label>
						<yesno required="required" />
						<help>You might have extracted data from another dataset, for example through an online service. Or you might have downloaded someone else's dataset and analysed it to create the data. In both these cases, we need to check that there are no legal barriers to you republishing the results of this data.</help>
						<if test="this.crowdsourced() === 'false'">
							<requirement test="this.thirdPartyOrigin() === 'true'">You have said that the data wasn't originally created or gathered by you, and wasn't crowd-sourced, so it must have been extracted or calculated from other data sources.</requirement>
						</if>
					</question>
					<if test="this.thirdPartyOrigin() === 'true'">
						<question id="thirdPartyOpen">
							<label>Are <em>all</em> the other data sources published as open data by their owners?</label>
							<yesno required="required" />
							<help>Open data is data that has been published under an open data licence or where the rights over that data have expired or been waived. If your data is created based on other data that is published as open data, then you can republish it. If your data incorporates data that is not published as open data, you will need to get legal advice to ensure that you can reuse that data and republish the results.</help>
							<if test="this.thirdPartyOpen() === 'false'">
								<requirement>You should get legal advice to ensure that you have the right to republish this data.</requirement>
							</if>
						</question>
					</if>
					<question id="crowdsourced">
						<label>Was some of this data crowd-sourced?</label>
						<yesno required="required" />
						<help>Crowd-sourcing involves collating data that is contributed by people operating outside your organisation. We ask about crowd-sourcing because if the data includes information that was contributed by others, you need to ensure that they granted their permission to publish their contributions as open data.</help>
						<if test="this.thirdPartyOrigin() === 'false'">
							<requirement test="this.crowdsourced() === 'true'">You have said that the data wasn't originally created or gathered by you, and wasn't extracted or calculated from other data, so it must have been crowd-sourced.</requirement>
						</if>
					</question>
					<if test="this.crowdsourced() === 'true'">
						<question id="crowdsourcedContent">
							<label>Did contributions require judgement?</label>
							<yesno required="required" />
							<help>The individuals who contributed to your data may have needed to employ their creativity or judgement to make their contributions. For example, writing a description or choosing whether or not to include some data in a dataset would require judgement. If judgement is involved, the contributors will have copyright over their contributions, so we will then need to check that they have transferred or waived their rights, or licensed the data, to you.</help>
						</question>
						<if test="this.crowdsourcedContent() === 'true'">
							<question id="claUrl">
								<label>Where is the Contributor Licence Agreement (CLA)?</label>
								<input type="url" placeholder="Contributor Licence Agreement URL" required="required" />
								<help more="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Contributor_License_Agreement">A Contributor Licence Agreement is an agreement with contributors that ensures that you can reuse the data that they contribute. It will either transfer the rights in the contributions to you, waive their rights, or license the data to you such that you can republish it.</help>
							</question>
							<question id="cldsRecorded">
								<label>Have all contributors agreed to the CLA?</label>
								<yesno required="required" />
								<help>All contributors need to agree to a Contributor Licence Agreement (CLA) so that you can reuse or republish their contributions. You should keep a record of who has provided contributions and whether or not they have agreed to the CLA.</help>
								<requirement>You must obtain agreement to a Contributor Licence Agreement from the contributors to your data to give you the right to republish their contributions as open data.</requirement>
							</question>
						</if>
					</if>
				</if>
			</if>
			<if test="this.publisherOrigin() === 'false'">
				<question id="sourceDocumentationUrl">
					<label>Where do you describe the sources of the data?</label>
					<input type="url" placeholder="Data Sources Documentation URL" />
					<help>If not all the data was originally created or gathered by you then even if you have the rights to publish it, it is good practice to document where the data was sourced from (its provenance) and the rights under which you are publishing the data.</help>
					<requirement level="pilot">You should document where the data was sourced from and the rights under which you are publishing the data so reusers are assured that they can reuse the parts sourced from third parties.</requirement>
				</question>
				<if test="this.sourceDocumentationUrl() !== ''">
					<question id="sourceDocumentationMetadata">
						<label>Does the documentation about the sources of the data include machine-readable data?</label>
						<yesno />
						<help>The documentation about the sources of the data needs to be human-readable, so that reusers can work out what it says, but it also helps if it contains machine-readable metadata. This helps those people who publish open data to find out how their data is being used, which helps them to justify its ongoing publication.</help>
						<requirement level="standard">You should include machine-readable data about the sources of data that you're using.</requirement>
					</question>
				</if>
			</if>
		</group>
		<group id="licensing">
			<label>Licensing</label>
			<help>giving other people permission to reuse the data</help>
			<question id="copyrightURL">
				<label>Where is your copyright statement?</label>
				<input type="url" />
				<help>A copyright statement states who owns the copyright and database rights in the data, and it says what you are allowing reusers can do with that data, usually by indicating its licence. We are asking where it is to check that you have one, to point reusers to it, and so we can automatically find out more about the terms under which you're making the data available.</help>
				<requirement level="pilot">You should have a page that states your copyright over the data and provides details of any attribution that people should use so that reusers understand how they can reuse it.</requirement>
			</question>
			<if test="this.copyrightURL() !== ''">
				<question id="copyrightStatementMetadata">
					<label>Does your copyright statement include machine-readable data for:</label>
					<!-- these are properties from the CC licensing vocabulary at http://creativecommons.org/ns -->
					<checkboxset>
						<option value="license">
							<label>licences</label>
							<requirement level="standard">You should provide machine-readable data in your copyright statement about the licences that should be used when the data is reused so that automated tools can flag the data as open data.</requirement>
						</option>
						<option value="attribution">
							<label>attribution</label>
							<requirement level="exemplar">You should provide machine-readable data in your copyright statement about the attribution that should be used when the data is reused so that automated tools can use the information.</requirement>
						</option>
						<option value="attributionURL">
							<label>attribution URL</label>
							<requirement level="exemplar">You should provide machine-readable data in your copyright statement about the URL that should be linked to when the data is reused so that automated tools can use the information.</requirement>
						</option>
						<option value="morePermissions">
							<label>additional permissions or alternative licences</label>
						</option>
						<option value="useGuidelines">
							<label>non-binding use guidelines</label>
						</option>
					</checkboxset>
					<help more="http://labs.creativecommons.org/2011/ccrel-guide/">If you have a copyright statement, it is good to embed within it machine-readable information about the licence under which you are making your data available. We can use this to automatically fill in parts of this questionnaire. Others can use it to automatically create attribution statements when they reuse your data.</help>
				</question>
			</if>
			<question id="dataLicence">
				<label>Under which licence can others reuse the data?</label>
				<select required="required">
					<option/>
					<option value="odc-by">Open Data Commons Attribution License</option>
					<option value="odc-by-sa">Open Data Commons Open Database License (ODbL)</option>
					<option value="pddl">Open Data Commons Public Domain Dedication and Licence (PDDL)</option>
					<option value="cc0">Creative Commons CCZero</option>
					<option value="ogl">UK Open Government Licence</option>
					<option value="na">Not applicable</option>
					<option value="other">Other...</option>
				</select>
				<help>The creator of a database automatically gets database rights where they spend substantial effort gathering, verifying and presenting data. You need to have a waiver or a licence that covers the database rights in the data so reusers know that they can reuse it. The licences that are listed here are the ones that are most commonly used; if there are no database rights, they've expired, or you've waived them, choose 'Not applicable'. We ask about the licence because we want to make sure that the data is actually open for others to reuse from a legal perspective.</help>
			</question>
			<if test="this.dataLicence() === 'na'">
				<question id="dataNotApplicable">
					<label>Why is a licence not applicable for this data?</label>
					<radioset required="required">
						<option value="norights">
							<label>there is no database right in this data</label>
							<help>You only have a database right in this data if you have spent substantial effort gathering, verifying or presenting the data. It's possible that there's no database right in the data, for example if the data is created from scratch, presented in an obvious way, and not checked against anything.</help>
						</option>
						<option value="expired">
							<label>the applicable database rights have expired</label>
							<help>Database rights last for ten years. If the data was last changed more than ten years ago, then the database rights within it will have expired.</help>
						</option>
						<option value="waived">
							<label>the applicable database rights have been waived</label>
							<help>You can waive your database rights, which means that no one owns them and anyone can do whatever they want with the data.</help>
						</option>
					</radioset>
				</question>
				<if test="this.dataNotApplicable() === 'waived'">
					<question id="dataWaiver">
						<label>Which waiver are you using to waive database rights?</label>
						<select required="required">
							<option/>
							<option value="pddl">Open Data Commons Public Domain Dedication and Licence (PDDL)</option>
							<option value="cc0">Creative Commons CCZero</option>
							<option value="other">Other...</option>
						</select>
						<help>If you waive your database right, you need to have a statement that says that you've done so, so that reusers know that they can do whatever they like with the data. There are existing waivers that you can use (PDDL and CCZero). You can author your own, but you should have legal advice if you do.</help>
					</question>
					<if test="this.dataWaiver() === 'other'">
						<question id="dataOtherWaiver">
							<label>Where is the waiver for the database rights?</label>
							<input type="url" required="required" placeholder="Waiver URL" />
							<help>If you have created your own waiver, we ask where it is so that we can check that it's publicly available and so that we can point reusers to it so they can check that it does in fact waive your database rights.</help>
						</question>
					</if>
				</if>
			</if>
			<if test="this.dataLicence() === 'other'">
				<question id="otherDataLicenceName">
					<label>What's the name of the licence?</label>
					<input required="required" />
					<help>If you are using another licence, we ask for its name so that we can refer to it within the Open Data Certificate.</help>
				</question>
				<question id="otherDataLicenceURL">
					<label>What's the location the licence?</label>
					<input type="url" required="required" />
					<help>If you are using another licence, we ask for a pointer to it so that we can link to it from within your Open Data Certificate and so that we can check that it is publicly accessible.</help>
				</question>
				<question id="otherDataLicenceOpen">
					<label>Is the licence an open licence?</label>
					<yesno required="required" />
					<help more="http://opendefinition.org/">The <a href="http://opendefinition.org/">Open Knowledge Definition</a> defines what an open data licence is and the <a href="">Open Definition Advisory Board</a> maintain a list of <a href="http://licenses.opendefinition.org/">open licences</a>. If the licence is not given in that list, it it is either not open or hasn't yet been assessed.</help>
					<requirement>You must publish open data under an open licence so that others can reuse it.</requirement>
				</question>
			</if>
			<question id="contentLicence">
				<label>Under which licence can others reuse the content?</label>
				<select required="required">
					<option/>
					<option value="cc-by">Creative Commons Attribution</option>
					<option value="cc-by-sa">Creative Commons Attribution Share-Alike</option>
					<option value="cc0">Creative Commons CCZero</option>
					<option value="ogl">UK Open Government Licence</option>
					<option value="na">Not applicable</option>
					<option value="other">Other...</option>
				</select>
				<help>The creator of content automatically gets copyright over that content when they spend intellectual effort creating it. Note that creative content does not include facts. You need to have a waiver or licence that covers the copyright in the data so reusers know that they can reuse it. The licences that are listed here are the ones that are most commonly used; if there is no copyright in the data, it's expired, or you've waived copyright, choose 'Not applicable'. We ask about the licence because we want to make sure that the data is actually open for others to reuse from a legal perspective.</help>
			</question>
			<if test="this.contentLicence() === 'na'">
				<question id="contentNotApplicable">
					<label>Why is a licence not applicable for this data?</label>
					<radioset required="required">
						<option value="norights">
							<label>there is no copyright in this data</label>
							<help>You only have a copyright in this data if you have spent creative intellectual effort creating it, for example by creating text that is included within the data, or exercising judgement in choosing whether particular data is included. It's possible that there's no copyright in the data, for example if it only contains facts with no judgement involved in selecting what to include.</help>
						</option>
						<option value="expired">
							<label>the applicable copyright has expired</label>
							<help>Copyright lasts for a fixed length of time, based on either a number of years after the death of its creator or the publication of the content. If the content was created or published a long time ago, the copyright may have expired.</help>
						</option>
						<option value="waived">
							<label>the applicable copyright has been waived</label>
							<help>You can waive your copyright, which means that no one owns it and anyone can do whatever they want with the data.</help>
						</option>
					</radioset>
				</question>
				<if test="this.contentNotApplicable() === 'waived'">
					<question id="contentWaiver">
						<label>Which waiver are you using to waive copyright?</label>
						<select required="required">
							<option/>
							<option value="cc0">Creative Commons CCZero</option>
							<option value="other">Other...</option>
						</select>
						<help>If you waive your copyright, you need to have a statement that says that you've done so, so that reusers know that they can do whatever they like with the data. You can use an existing waiver (CCZero) or you can author your own, but you should have legal advice if you do.</help>
					</question>
					<if test="this.contentWaiver() === 'other'">
						<question id="contentOtherWaiver">
							<label>Where is the waiver for the copyright?</label>
							<input type="url" required="required" placeholder="Waiver URL" />
							<help>If you have created your own waiver, we ask where it is so that we can check that it's publicly available and so that we can point reusers to it so they can check that it does in fact waive your copyright.</help>
						</question>
					</if>
				</if>
			</if>
			<if test="this.contentLicence() === 'other'">
				<question id="otherContentLicenceName">
					<label>What's the name of the licence?</label>
					<input required="required" placeholder="Licence Name" />
					<help>If you are using another licence, we ask for its name so that we can refer to it within the Open Data Certificate.</help>
				</question>
				<question id="otherContentLicenceURL">
					<label>What's the location the licence?</label>
					<input type="url" required="required" placeholder="Licence URL" />
					<help>If you are using another licence, we ask for a pointer to it so that we can link to it from within your Open Data Certificate and so that we can check that it is publicly accessible.</help>
				</question>
				<question id="otherContentLicenceOpen">
					<label>Is the licence an open licence?</label>
					<yesno required="required" />
					<help more="http://opendefinition.org/">The <a href="http://opendefinition.org/">Open Knowledge Definition</a> defines what an open data licence is and the <a href="">Open Definition Advisory Board</a> maintain a list of <a href="http://licenses.opendefinition.org/">open licences</a>. If the licence is not given in that list, it it is either not open or hasn't yet been assessed.</help>
					<requirement>You must publish open data under an open licence so that others can reuse it.</requirement>
				</question>
			</if>
		</group>
		<group id="privacy">
			<label>Privacy</label>
			<help>ensuring that you protect people's privacy</help>
			<question id="dataPersonal">
				<label>Could the source of this data be personal data under the Data Protection Act?</label>
				<radioset required="pilot">
					<option value="not-personal">
						<label>no, the data could never be personal data as it is not about people or their activity</label>
						<help>Data that is about the activity of people can be personal data if there's the potential for it to be combined with other data to identify individuals. For example, data about road traffic flows is about people's activity and could be combined with other information (about an individual's commuting patterns) to reveal information about that individual.</help>
					</option>
					<option value="personal">
						<label>yes, the source of this data is classified as personal data within your organisation</label>
						<help more="http://www.ico.org.uk/for_organisations/data_protection/the_guide/key_definitions">Personal data is data that relates to a living individual who can be identified from the data or from the data in combination with other information. If your organisation has other information that can be used to identify the individuals in the source of this data, then it must be classified as personal data within your organisation.</help>
					</option>
					<option value="possibly">
						<label>yes, the source of this data could be classified as personal data if held by other people who have access to additional information</label>
						<help more="http://www.ico.org.uk/for_organisations/data_protection/the_guide/key_definitions">Personal data is data that relates to a living individual who can be identified from the data or from the data in combination with other information. Even if your organisation doesn't have other information that could be used to identify the individuals in the source of this data, it may be that other people do have access to such information.</help>
					</option>
				</radioset>
			</question>
			<if test="this.dataPersonal() === 'personal' || this.dataPersonal() === 'possibly'">
				<question id="consentExempt">
					<label>Is this data exempt from the non-disclosure provisions of the Data Protection Act?</label>
					<yesno required="pilot" />
					<help more="http://www.ico.org.uk/for_organisations/data_protection/the_guide/exemptions">There are exemptions from the non-disclosure provisions of the Data Protection Act, which mean that organisations do not have to comply with the normal non-disclosure provisions.</help>
				</question>
				<if test="this.consentExempt() === 'false'">
					<question id="privacyImpactAssessmentUrl">
						<label>Where is your privacy impact assessment published?</label>
						<input type="url" placeholder="Privacy Impact Assessment URL"/>
						<help more="http://www.ico.gov.uk/for_organisations/data_protection/topic_guides/privacy_impact_assessment.aspx">A <a href="http://www.ico.gov.uk/for_organisations/data_protection/topic_guides/privacy_impact_assessment.aspx">Privacy Impact Assessment</a> is a process for identifying privacy risks to individuals in the collection, use and disclosure of information. We ask where it is published because this enables us to check that it exists.</help>
						<requirement level="pilot">You should carry out a a privacy impact assessment to identify risks of releasing the data, mitigations against those risks, and to put in place processes that ensure that any breaches are handled effectively.</requirement>
					</question>
					<if test="this.privacyImpactAssessmentUrl() !== ''">
						<question id="piaAudited">
							<label>Has your Privacy Impact Assessment been independently audited?</label>
							<yesno />
							<help>An independent audit of a privacy impact assessment will check that the assessment has been carried out correctly. We ask if it has been independently audited to assess the rigour of the privacy impact assessment.</help>
							<requirement level="standard">You should have your privacy impact assessment independently audited to ensure that it has been carried out correctly.</requirement>
						</question>
					</if>
					<question id="individualConsentURL">
						<label>Where is the privacy notice you provide to affected individuals published?</label>
						<input type="url" placeholder="Privacy Notice URL" />
						<help more="http://www.ico.org.uk/for_organisations/data_protection/the_guide/principle_2">Unless you are exempt from the non-disclosure provisions of the Data Protection Act, you are required to give individuals privacy notices when collecting data about them, which should specify the purposes for which that data will be used. We ask where these are because reusers need to be able to look at them so that they can stick within the confines of the Data Protection Act when they are handling the data.</help>
						<requirement level="pilot">You should inform potential reusers about the purposes of processing personal data which individuals were informed of, so that reusers can comply with the Data Protection Act and use the data consistently with that consent.</requirement>
					</question>
					<question id="personalDataAnonymisation">
						<label>Has your anonymisation approach been audited?</label>
						<yesno />
						<help>An audit of your anonymisation approach will ensure that you have carried out the appropriate anonymisation technique for your data, and carried it out effectively. This can be done by a specialist within your organisation or an independent third party.</help>
						<requirement level="pilot">You should engage an expert to audit your anonymisation approach to ensure that it is appropriate for your data.</requirement>
					</question>
				</if>
				<if test="this.consentExempt() === 'true'">
					<question id="privacyImpactAssessment">
						<label>Have you carried out a privacy impact assessment?</label>
						<yesno />
						<help more="http://www.ico.gov.uk/for_organisations/data_protection/topic_guides/privacy_impact_assessment.aspx">A <a href="http://www.ico.gov.uk/for_organisations/data_protection/topic_guides/privacy_impact_assessment.aspx">Privacy Impact Assessment</a> is a process for identifying privacy risks to individuals in the collection, use and disclosure of information. Even if you are exempt from the non-disclosure provisions of the Data Protection Act, you should carry out a privacy impact assessment so that you are aware of the possible risks of making the data open. We do not expect you to publish this privacy impact assessment because it might contain sensitive information about the risks that you are prepared to take.</help>
						<requirement level="standard">You should carry out a a privacy impact assessment to identify risks of releasing the data, mitigations against those risks, and to put in place processes that ensure that any breaches are handled effectively.</requirement>
					</question>
				</if>
			</if>
		</group>
	</group>
	<group id="practical">
		<label>Practical Information</label>
		<group id="findability">
			<label>Findability</label>
			<help>helping reusers to locate the data</help>
			<question id="linkedTo">
				<label>Is documentation about the data findable within three clicks of your organisation's home page?</label>
				<yesno />
				<help>The documentation about the data that should be findable is the page that you have given as the Documentation URL. This should be findable by clicking on links from the home page of your organisation (not through searching).</help>
				<requirement level="standard">You should ensure that reusers can easily find your data from your organisation's home page.</requirement>
			</question>
			<question id="listed">
				<label>Is the data listed somewhere, alongside data from the wider sector?</label>
				<yesno />
				<help>You can make your data easier to find by making sure that it is listed within relevant data catalogs and by ensuring it turns up in relevant search results.</help>
				<requirement level="standard">You should ensure that reusers can locate your data through searching for it in locations that list available data.</requirement>
			</question>
			<if test="this.listed() === 'true'">
				<repeat id="listings">
					<label>Listing</label>
					<question id="listing">
						<label>Where is the data listed?</label>
						<input type="url" required="required" placeholder="Listing URL" />
						<help>Give a URL that leads to a listing of this data alongside data from the wider sector.  For example, give a URL for a search that includes this data's listing on data.gov.uk (if it's UK public sector data), hub.data.ac.uk (if it's UK academia data), MEDIN (if it's marine data), or the URL of a search on Google or Bing.</help>
					</question>
				</repeat>
			</if>
		</group>
		<group id="accuracy">
			<label>Accuracy</label>
			<help>providing assurance that the data is up to date</help>
			<if test="this.releaseType() === 'service'">
				<question id="serviceType">
					<label>Does the data underlying the API change over time?</label>
					<radioset required="pilot">
						<option value="static">
							<label>no, the API simply provides easy access to unchanging data</label>
							<help>Some APIs are created by processing a single unchanging dataset: the purpose of the API is to make accessing this data easier, particularly when there is lots of that data.</help>
						</option>
						<option value="changing">
							<label>yes, the API provides instant access to changing data</label>
							<help>Some APIs are created over changeable data, and the primary purpose of the API is to provide up-to-date access to this data.</help>
						</option>
					</radioset>
				</question>
			</if>
			<if test="this.releaseType() === 'oneoff' || this.releaseType() === 'collection' || (this.releaseType() === 'service' &amp;&amp; this.serviceType() === 'static')">
				<question id="timeSensitive">
					<label>Will this data go out of date?</label>
					<radioset>
						<option value="true">
							<label>yes, this data will go out of date over time</label>
							<help>For example, a dataaset that contains the current location of bus stops will go out of date over time, as some bus stops are moved or new bus stops created.</help>
						</option>
						<option value="timestamped">
							<label>yes, this data will go out of date over time but the data is timestamped</label>
							<help>For example, demography statistics usually include a timestamp to indicate the time at which the statistics were relevant.</help>
							<requirement level="pilot">You should include timestamps in your data when releasing data that will go out of date over time, so that reusers know the time period it relates to.</requirement>
						</option>
						<option value="false">
							<label>no, this data does not contain any time-sensitive information</label>
							<help>For example, a dataset that contains the results of an experiment will not go out of date because the data accurately reports the results of the experiment.</help>
							<requirement level="standard">You should publish updates to data that goes out of date so that the information you provide does not go stale.</requirement>
						</option>
					</radioset>
				</question>
			</if>
			<if test="this.releaseType() === 'series'">
				<question id="frequentChanges">
					<label>Does the data you capture change on at least a daily basis?</label>
					<yesno required="pilot" />
					<help>Indicate whether you create or gather new data continuously, such that the underlying data changes most days. We ask about this because when data changes frequently it also goes out of date quickly, so we need to check that the releases that you are making are also made quickly and frequently.</help>
				</question>			
				<if test="this.frequentChanges() === 'true'">
					<question id="seriesType">
						<label>What type of dataset series is this?</label>
						<radioset required="exemplar">
							<option value="dumps">
								<label>regular copies of the complete database</label>
								<help>Select this option if you are publishing copies of the contents of your database at regular intervals. For example, you would choose this option if you had a database of bus stops and created a new, updated, version of that dataset every day. We ask this because when you are creating database dumps, it is often useful for reusers to be able to access a feed of the changes to the database so that they can keep their copies up to date.</help>
							</option>
							<option value="aggregate">
								<label>regular aggregates of changing data</label>
								<help>Select this option if you are creating new datasets at regular intervals. This might be because you are creating aggregates because the underlying data cannot be released as open data. Or it might be that you only publish the data that is new since the last publication.</help>
							</option>
						</radioset>
					</question>
					<if test="this.seriesType() === 'dumps'">
						<question id="changeFeed">
							<label>Is a feed of changes made available?</label>
							<yesno />
							<help>Indicate whether you make available a feed of the changes that occur to the data that you capture, such as new entries or amendments to existing entries. A feed might be in a format such as RSS or Atom, or a custom data format.</help>
							<requirement level="exemplar">You should provide a feed of changes in your data so that it's easy for reusers to keep their copies up to date.</requirement>
						</question>
					</if>
					<question id="frequentSeriesPublication">
						<label>How frequently do you create a new release?</label>
						<radioset>
							<option value="rarely">
								<label>less frequently than once a month</label>
							</option>
							<option value="monthly">
								<label>at least every month</label>
								<requirement level="pilot">You should create a new dataset release every month so that reusers can access up-to-date information.</requirement>
							</option>
							<option value="weekly">
								<label>at least every week</label>
								<requirement level="standard">You should create a new dataset release every week so that reusers can access up-to-date information.</requirement>
							</option>
							<option value="daily">
								<label>at least every day</label>
								<requirement level="exemplar">You should create a new dataset release every day so that reusers can access up-to-date information.</requirement>
							</option>
						</radioset>
						<help>We ask about the frequency with which you publish new datasets in the series because this determines how out of date the data that you are making available will get before reusers can get an update to their data.</help>
					</question>
				</if>
				<question id="seriesPublicationDelay">
					<label>What is the delay between creating a dataset and publishing it?</label>
					<radioset>
						<option value="extreme">
							<label>longer than the gap between releases</label>
							<help>For example, if you are creating a new version of the dataset every day, then choose this option if it takes more than a day for the dataset to then be published.</help>
						</option>
						<option value="reasonable">
							<label>about the same as the gap between releases</label>
							<help>For example, if you are creating a new version of the dataset every day, then choose this option if it takes about a day for the dataset to then be published.</help>
							<requirement level="pilot">You should have a delay between creating and publishing a dataset that is less than the gap between releases so that reusers can access up-to-date information.</requirement>
						</option>
						<option value="good">
							<label>less than half the gap between releases</label>
							<help>For example, if you are creating a new version of the dataset every day, then choose this option if it takes less than twelve hours for the data to then be published.</help>
							<requirement level="standard">You should have a delay between creating and publishing a dataset that is less than half the gap between releases so that reusers can access up-to-date information.</requirement>
						</option>
						<option value="minimal">
							<label>there is minimal or no delay</label>
							<help>Choose this option if the delay is in the order of a few seconds if the datasets are created frequently, or a few minutes if they are made less frequently.</help>
							<requirement level="exemplar">You should have minimal or no delay between creating and publishing datasets so that reusers can access up-to-date information.</requirement>
						</option>
					</radioset>
				</question>
			</if>
			<if test="this.releaseType() === 'service'">
				<question id="provideDumps">
					<label>Do you also provide dumps of the dataset?</label>
					<yesno />
					<help>A dump is an extract of the data into a static file that developers can download to get hold of the whole dataset. Being able to access a dump of the whole dataset enables different kinds of analyses than API access.</help>
					<requirement level="standard">You should enable reusers to download the entire dataset so that they can analyse it in its entirety.</requirement>
				</question>
				<if test="this.serviceType() === 'changing'">
					<if test="this.provideDumps() === 'true'">
						<question id="dumpFrequency">
							<label>How frequently do you create a new dump?</label>
							<radioset>
								<option value="rarely">
									<label>less frequently than once a month</label>
								</option>
								<option value="monthly">
									<label>at least every month</label>
									<requirement level="pilot">You should create a new database dump every month, so that new reusers can get hold of an up-to-date dump.</requirement>
								</option>
								<option value="weekly">
									<label>within a week of any change</label>
									<requirement level="standard">You should create a new database dump within a week of any change, so that new reusers do not have long to wait for an up-to-date dump.</requirement>
								</option>
								<option value="daily">
									<label>within a day of any change</label>
									<requirement level="exemplar">You should create a new database dump within a day of any change, so that new reusers can easily get hold of an up-to-date dump.</requirement>
								</option>
							</radioset>
							<help>Providing new database dumps within a short period ensures that new developers can get started with up-to-date data whenever they start looking at the data.</help>
						</question>
					</if>
				</if>
				<if test="this.timeSensitive() !== 'true'">
					<question id="corrected">
						<label>Will this data be corrected if it contains errors?</label>
						<yesno />
						<help>Indicate whether the data will be corrected in cases where errors are discovered within the data. We ask this because it is good practice to correct data that is revealed to contain errors (especially as you should be using this data yourself), and because if you do correct the data you need to provide additional support for reusers who will need to be informed of these corrections.</help>
						<requirement level="standard">You should correct data that is found to contain errors so that all users benefit from improvements in accuracy.</requirement>
					</question>
				</if>
			</if>
		</group>
		<group id="quality">
			<label>Quality</label>
			<help>helping reusers to understand where there might be problems in the data</help>
			<question id="qualityUrl">
				<label>Where are known issues with the quality of the data documented?</label>
				<input type="url" placeholder="Quality Issues URL" />
				<help>There are usually areas within any non-trivial data where there are known quality problems. For example, maybe the equipment that collected the data malfunctioned for a day, or the data was migrated between two systems and errors crept in during that migration. Documenting these helps reusers to have a better understanding of the data that they are using.</help>
				<requirement level="standard">You should document any known issues with the quality of the data so that reusers can understand how much they can rely on the data.</requirement>
			</question>
			<question id="qualityControlUrl">
				<label>Where is your quality control process described?</label>
				<input type="url" placeholder="Quality Control Process Description URL" />
				<help>A quality control process checks the quality of the data on an ongoing basis, either by hand or automatically, or through a combination of techniques. Having a publicly available description of your quality control process reassures reusers that you are checking the quality of the data that you are making available, and helps them to identify places that could be improved.</help>
				<requirement level="exemplar">You should document your quality control process so that reusers can understand how much they can rely on the data.</requirement>
			</question>
		</group>
		<group id="guarantees">
			<label>Guarantees</label>
			<help>helping reusers to understand how much to rely on the data</help>
			<if test="this.releaseType() === 'service'">
				<question id="serviceAvailability">
					<label>What is the guaranteed availability of the service?</label>
					<radioset>
						<option value="minimal">
							<label>there are minimal guarantees about the availability of the service</label>
						</option>
						<option value="99">
							<label>at least 99% availability</label>
							<requirement level="pilot">You should guarantee at least 99% availability (less than 3.65 days downtime/year) of the service so that reusers know they can rely on it.</requirement>
						</option>
						<option value="99.9">
							<label>at least 99.9% availability</label>
							<requirement level="standard">You should guarantee at least 99.9% availability (less than 8.76 hours downtime/year) of the service so that reusers know they can rely on it.</requirement>
						</option>
						<option value="99.999">
							<label>at least 99.999% availability</label>
							<requirement level="exemplar">You should guarantee at least 99.999% availability (less than 5.26 minutes downtime/year) of the service so that reusers know they can rely on it.</requirement>
						</option>
					</radioset>
					<help>You will probably have in place a service-level agreement (SLA) with the service provider for the servers that you are using to host the data. These SLAs should indicate guaranteed up-time for the servers, and hence the availability of your data.</help>
				</question>
			</if>
			<question id="onGoingAvailability">
				<label>For how long will the data be available in this way?</label>
				<radioset>
					<option value="experimental">
						<label>this data may disappear at any time</label>
					</option>
					<option value="short">
						<label>this data is available experimentally but should be around for another year or so</label>
						<requirement level="pilot">You should provide a guarantee to reusers that the data will be available in this form for about a year so that they know they can rely on it.</requirement>
					</option>
					<option value="medium">
						<label>this data is included in your medium-term plans and should therefore be around for a couple of years</label>
						<requirement level="standard">You should provide a guarantee to reusers that the data will be available in this form in the medium term so that they know they can rely on it.</requirement>
					</option>
					<option value="long">
						<label>this data is part of your business-as-usual operation and will continue to be published long term</label>
						<requirement level="exemplar">You should provide a guarantee to reusers that the data will be available in this form long term so that they know they can rely on it.</requirement>
					</option>
				</radioset>
			</question>
		</group>
	</group>
	<group id="technical">
		<label>Technical Information</label>
		<if test="this.releaseType() !== ''">
			<group id="locations">
				<label>Locations</label>
				<help>helping reusers to access the data</help>
				<if test="this.releaseType() === 'oneoff'">
					<question id="datasetUrl">
						<label>What's the URL of the dataset?</label>
						<input type="url" placeholder="Dataset URL" />
						<help>This should be the URL of the dataset itself (for example a CSV file). This is a different URL from the page that describes the dataset. We ask this to ensure that the dataset is available on the web, and that it can be linked to directly, as this helps reusers to access the data.</help>
						<if test="this.documentationUrl() === ''">
							<requirement test="this.datasetUrl() !== ''">You must provide either a URL for the dataset or a URL for documentation about it so that reusers can find it.</requirement>
						</if>
						<if test="this.documentationUrl() !== ''">
							<requirement test="this.datasetUrl() !== ''" level="pilot">You should have a URL that is a direct link to the data itself so that reusers can access it easily.</requirement>
						</if>
					</question>
				</if>
				<if test="this.releaseType() === 'series'">
					<question id="versionManagement">
						<label>How do you publish the datasets in the series?</label>
						<checkboxset>
							<option value="current">
								<label>the data at a single "current" dataset URL is regularly updated</label>
								<help>Having a single "current" dataset URL means that there is one URL from which reusers can always download the most recent version of the dataset.</help>
								<requirement level="standard">You should have a single URL that can always be used to download the current version of the dataset so that reusers can access it easily.</requirement>
							</option>
							<option value="template">
								<label>the URLs for each release follow a regular pattern</label>
								<help>Having URLs that follow a regular pattern means publishing datsets at URLs where the date of publication is part of the URL itself. For example, if you published a dataset each month then you would include the month (eg <code>2013-04</code>) as part of the URL. This helps reusers to understand when the dataset dates from, and helps them write scripts that collect together all the published datasets or fetch new ones each time they're released.</help>
								<requirement level="pilot">You should use a regular pattern in the URLs for different releases so that reusers can easily get hold of each of those releases.</requirement>
							</option>
							<option value="list">
								<label>you publish a list of the releases</label>
								<help>Having a list of the releases means having a web page or a feed (such as Atom or RSS) that contains details of each release, including a link through to each individual release and a description of when it dates from. Reusers can use these lists to understand the frequency and regularity of your publication, and to help them write scripts that collect together all the published datasets or fetch new ones each time they're released.</help>
								<requirement level="standard">You should have a document or feed that provides a list of all the available releases so that reusers can create scripts to download all of them.</requirement>
							</option>
						</checkboxset>
						<if test="this.documentationUrl() === '' &amp;&amp; this.versionManagementStatus() !== 'complete'">
							<requirement>You must provide access to releases of your data through a current URL, a discoverable series of URLs or through a documentation page so that reusers can locate it.</requirement>
						</if>
					</question>
					<if test="this.versionManagement().current">
						<question id="currentDatasetUrl">
							<label>What's the URL of the current dataset?</label>
							<input type="url" placeholder="Current Dataset URL" required="required" />
							<help>This should be the single URL that always gives the current version of the dataset itself (for example a CSV file). The content at this URL should change each time a new version is released. This should not be a page describing the dataset.</help>
						</question>
					</if>
					<if test="this.versionManagement().template">
						<question id="versionsTemplateUrl">
							<label>What's the URL template for the releases?</label>
							<input type="url" placeholder="Version Template URL" required="required" />
							<help>This should be a template that outlines the structure of the URLs that are used when publishing different releases. Use <code>{<var>variable</var>}</code> within the URL template to indicate changeable parts of the URL. For example <code>http://example.com/data/monthly/mydata-{YY}{MM}.csv</code></help>
						</question>
					</if>
					<if test="this.versionManagement().list">
						<question id="versionsUrl">
							<label>What's the URL that gives a list of releases?</label>
							<input type="url" placeholder="Version List URL" required="required" />
							<help>This should be the URL of a page or feed that provides a machine-readable list of the previous versions of the dataset. If the list goes over several pages, then give the URL of the first page and make sure there are links to other pages.</help>
						</question>
					</if>
				</if>
				<if test="this.releaseType() === 'service'">
					<question id="endpointUrl">
						<label>What's the endpoint for the API?</label>
						<input type="url" placeholder="Endpoint URL" />
						<help>This should be a URL that provides a starting point for scripts that access the API. If the API supports it, this should be a service description document, which enables the script to work out the kinds of services that are offered by the API.</help>
						<if test="this.documentationUrl() === ''">
							<requirement test="this.endpointUrl() !== ''">You must provide either a URL for the API endpoint or a URL for the documentation about it so that reusers can find it.</requirement>
						</if>
						<if test="this.documentationUrl() !== ''">
							<requirement test="this.endpointUrl() !== ''" level="standard">You should have a service description document or similar single entry point for your API so that reusers can access it.</requirement>
						</if>
					</question>
					<if test="this.provideDumps() === 'true'">
						<question id="dumpManagement">
							<label>How do you publish the database dumps?</label>
							<checkboxset>
								<option value="current">
									<label>the data at a single "current" dump URL is regularly updated</label>
									<help>Having a single "current" dump URL means that there is one URL from which reusers can always download the most recently created dump.</help>
									<requirement level="standard">You should have a single URL that can always be used to download the current dump of the database so that reusers can find it.</requirement>
								</option>
								<option value="template">
									<label>the URLs for each release follow a regular pattern</label>
									<help>Having URLs that follow a regular pattern means publishing dumps at URLs where the date of publication is part of the URL itself. For example, if you published a dump each month then you would include the month (eg <code>2013-04</code>) as part of the URL. This helps reusers to understand when the dump dates from, and helps them write scripts that collect together all the published dumps (to carry out comparisons, for example) or fetch new ones each time they're released.</help>
									<requirement level="exemplar">You should use a regular pattern in the URLs for different dumps so that reusers can easily get hold of the dump for a particular time period.</requirement>
								</option>
								<option value="list">
									<label>you publish a list of the releases</label>
									<help>Having a list of the dumps means having a web page or a feed (such as Atom or RSS) that contains details of each dump, including a link through to each individual release and a description of when it dates from. Reusers can use these lists to understand the frequency and regularity of your publication, and to help them write scripts that collect together all the published datasets or fetch new ones each time they're released.</help>
									<requirement level="exemplar">You should have a document or feed that provides a list of all the available dumps so that reusers can create scripts to download all of them.</requirement>
								</option>
							</checkboxset>
						</question>
						<if test="this.dumpManagement().current">
							<question id="currentDumpUrl">
								<label>What's the URL of the current dump?</label>
								<input type="url" placeholder="Current Dump URL" required="required" />
								<help>This should be the URL that always gives the most recent dump of the database itself (for example as a CSV file). The content at this URL should change each time a new dump is created.</help>
							</question>
						</if>
						<if test="this.dumpManagement().template">
							<question id="dumpsTemplateUrl">
								<label>What's the URL template for the dumps?</label>
								<input type="url" placeholder="Dump Template URL" required="required" />
								<help>This should be a template that outlines the structure of the URLs that are used when publishing different dumps. Use <code>{<var>variable</var>}</code> within the URL template to indicate changeable parts of the URL. For example <code>http://example.com/data/monthly/mydata-{YY}{MM}.csv</code></help>
							</question>
						</if>
						<if test="this.dumpManagement().list">
							<question id="dumpsUrl">
								<label>What's the URL that gives a list of available dumps?</label>
								<input type="url" placeholder="Dump List URL" required="required" />
								<help>Enter the URL of a page or feed that provides a machine-readable list of the available dumps of the database.</help>
							</question>
						</if>
					</if>
				</if>
				<if test="this.changeFeed() === 'true'">
					<question id="changeFeedUrl">
						<label>What's the URL that provides a feed of changes?</label>
						<input type="url" placeholder="Change Feed URL" required="required" />
						<help>This should be the URL of a page or feed that provides a machine-readable list of the previous versions of the dataset. If the list goes over several pages, then give the URL of the first page and make sure there are links to other pages.</help>
					</question>
				</if>
			</group>
		</if>
		<group id="format">
			<label>Formats</label>
			<help>helping reusers to work with the data</help>
			<question id="machineReadable">
				<label>Is the data machine-readable?</label>
				<yesno />
				<help>A machine-readable format is one in which the information can be easily extracted from the data by a computer. For example, scanned photocopies of spreadsheets would not be machine-readable, but a CSV file would be.</help>
				<requirement level="pilot">You should provide the data in a machine-readable format so that it's easy to reuse.</requirement>
			</question>
			<question id="openStandard">
				<label>Is the data in an open standard format?</label>
				<yesno />
				<help more="https://www.gov.uk/government/uploads/system/uploads/attachment_data/file/183962/Open-Standards-Principles-FINAL.pdf">An open standard is one that is written through a defined fair, transparent and collaborative process and that anyone can implement. For example, XML, CSV and JSON are open standards.</help>
				<requirement level="standard">You should provide the data in an open standard format so that reusers can use common tools to process it.</requirement>
			</question>
			<question id="dataType">
				<label>What kind of data are you publishing?</label>
				<checkboxset required="pilot">
					<option value="documents">
						<label>human-readable documents</label>
						<help>Human-readable documents are those that are intended for human consumption. Examples would be policy documents, white papers, reports, meeting minutes and so on. These will usually have some structure to them, but the majority of the information within them is text.</help>
					</option>
					<option value="statistical">
						<label>statistical data, such as counts, averages and percentages</label>
						<help>Statistical data includes numeric data such as counts, averages or percentages. Examples would be census results, traffic flow information or crime statistics.</help>
					</option>
					<option value="geographic">
						<label>geographic information, such as points and boundaries</label>
						<help>Geographic information is any data that can be plotted on a map. These may be points or boundaries or lines.</help>
					</option>
					<option value="structured">
						<label>other kinds of structured data</label>
						<help>Other kinds of structured data would include things like event details, railway timetables, contact information: anything that can be interpreted as data, analysed and presented in multiple ways.</help>
					</option>
				</checkboxset>
			</question>
			<if test="this.dataType().documents">
				<question id="documentFormat">
					<label>Do the formats used for documents include:</label>
					<radioset>
						<option value="semantic">
							<label>one that exposes the semantic structure of documents, such as HTML, Docbook or Markdown</label>
							<help>Documents are typically structured into chapters or sections, with headings and tables, lists and figures, terms and their definitions. Formats such as HTML, Docbook and Markdown that label these structures make it easy to automatically create summaries such as tables of contents and glossaries, and make it easy to apply different styling to the document to make it appear differently.</help>
							<requirement level="standard">You should publish documents in a format that exposes their semantic structure so that it's easy to display in different styles.</requirement>
						</option>
						<option value="format">
							<label>one that focuses on the format of documents, such as OOXML or PDF</label>
							<help>Because documents are made for human consumption, they are typically created with great emphasis on how the document looks. Formats such as OOXML and PDF emphasise appearance: the use of particular fonts and colours and the positioning of different elements within the page. These are good for human consumption, but (despite being machine-readable) aren't as easy for machines to process or re-style.</help>
							<requirement level="pilot">You should publish documents in a format that is designed for documents so that it's easy to process.</requirement>
						</option>
						<option value="unsuitable">
							<label>only those not designed for documents, such as Excel, JSON or CSV</label>
							<help>Formats such as Excel or CSV are suited to tabular data. Formats such as JSON are suited for structured data. Because of the way they are structured, documents aren't suited to these formats.</help>
						</option>
					</radioset>
				</question>
			</if>
			<if test="this.dataType().statistical">
				<question id="statisticalFormat">
					<label>Do the formats used for statistical data include:</label>
					<radioset>
						<option value="statistical">
							<label>one that exposes the structure of the statistical hypercube data, such as SDMX or Data Cube</label>
							<help>Statistical data typically fits into a hypercube in which individual observations are related to a particular measure and a set of dimensions. Each observation may also be related to a number of annotations that provide additional context. Formats such as <a href="http://sdmx.org/">SDMX</a> and <a href="http://www.w3.org/TR/vocab-data-cube/">Data Cube</a> are designed to express this underlying structure of statistical data.</help>
							<requirement level="exemplar">You should publish statistical data in a format that exposes its dimensions and measures so that it's easy to analyse.</requirement>
						</option>
						<option value="tabular">
							<label>one that treats the statistical data as a table, such as CSV</label>
							<help>Statistical data can be arranged within a table of rows and columns. This lacks the expressiveness about the underlying hypercube, but is easy to process.</help>
							<requirement level="standard">You should publish tabular data in a format that exposes the tables of data so that it's easy to analyse.</requirement>
						</option>
						<option value="format">
							<label>one that focuses on the format of tabular data, such as Excel</label>
							<help>Excel and other spreadsheet formats typically emphasise the appearance of data, using italic or bold text, or indentation within fields, or the width of lines between rows, to indicate its underlying structure. This styling helps humans to understand the meaning of the data, but is hard for computers to interpret, and thus makes the data less reusable than it might otherwise be.</help>
							<requirement level="pilot">You should publish tabular data in a format that is designed for tabular data so that it's easy to process.</requirement>
						</option>
						<option value="unsuitable">
							<label>only those not designed for statistical or tabular data, such as Word or PDF</label>
							<help>Formats that are oriented towards human-readable documents, such as Word or PDF, are not suitable for statistical data, as they completely obscure the underlying structure of the data.</help>
						</option>
					</radioset>
				</question>
			</if>
			<if test="this.dataType().geographic">
				<question id="geographicFormat">
					<label>Do the formats used for geographic data include:</label>
					<radioset>
						<option value="specific">
							<label>one designed for geographic data, such as KML or GeoJSON</label>
							<help>Geographic data describes points, lines and boundaries. Formats that are designed for geographic data expose these kinds of structures in the data, which makes it easier to process automatically.</help>
							<requirement level="standard">You should publish geographic data in a format designed for geographic data so that it's easy to use with existing tools.</requirement>
						</option>
						<option value="generic">
							<label>a generic structured data format, such as JSON, XML or CSV</label>
							<help>Geographic data can be expressed using any format that can be used for normal structured data, particularly if it only holds data about points.</help>
							<requirement level="pilot">You should publish geographic data as structured data so that it's easy to process.</requirement>
						</option>
						<option value="unsuitable">
							<label>only those not designed for geographic data, such as Word or PDF</label>
							<help>Formats that are oriented towards human-readable documents, such as Word or PDF, are not suitable for geographic data, as they completely obscure the underlying structure of the data.</help>
						</option>
					</radioset>
				</question>
			</if>
			<if test="this.dataType().structured">
				<question id="structuredFormat">
					<label>Do the formats used for structured data include:</label>
					<radioset>
						<option value="suitable">
							<label>one designed for structured data, such as JSON, XML, Turtle or CSV</label>
							<help>Structured data formats break down data into a basic structure of things which have values for a known set of properties. These predictable formats are easy for machines to process.</help>
							<requirement level="pilot">You should publish structured data in a format designed for structured data so that it's easy to process.</requirement>
						</option>
						<option value="unsuitable">
							<label>only those not designed for structured data, such as Word or PDF</label>
							<help>Formats that are oriented towards human-readable documents, such as Word or PDF, are not suitable for structured data, as they completely obscure its underlying structure.</help>
						</option>
					</radioset>
				</question>
			</if>
			<question id="identifiers">
				<label>Are you using URLs to identify things in the data?</label>
				<yesno />
				<help>Data is usually about things, often things in the real world such as schools and roads. Identifying these things using URLs provides a mechanism for people to find out more about the thing that is being described by the data. If data from different sources consistently uses the same URL to refer to the same thing, those different data sources can be combined easily, to create more useful data. URLs can usefully be used in place of identifying numbers or codes.</help>
				<requirement level="standard">You should use URLs to identify things in the data, so that they can be easily referenced and combined with other data about those things.</requirement>
			</question>
			<if test="this.identifiers() === 'true'">
				<question id="resolvingUrls">
					<label>Do the URLs resolve to information about those things?</label>
					<yesno />
					<help>A URL that resolves to information about something is one that, when put in a browser, provides you with additional data. For example there are resolvable URLs for <a href="http://opencorporates.com/companies/gb/08030289">companies</a> and <a href="http://data.ordnancesurvey.co.uk/doc/postcodeunit/EC2A4JE">postcodes</a>. These provide human-readable pages but are also linked to underlying data which scripts can process.</help>
					<requirement level="exemplar">You should provide a page of information about each of the things in your data so that reusers can easily find and share that information.</requirement>
				</question>
				<question id="existingExternalUrls">
					<label>Do external URLs exist for any of those things?</label>
					<yesno required="exemplar" />
					<help>These may be other websites, outside your control, that provide URLs for the things that you are naming through URLs within your data. For example, your data might include postcodes, when there are URLs for postcodes that are supported on the Ordnance Survey website.</help>
				</question>
				<if test="this.existingExternalUrls() === 'true'">
					<question id="reliableExternalUrls">
						<label>Do those external URLs serve reliable data?</label>
						<yesno required="exemplar" />
						<help>Just because other websites support URLs for things (such as companies or postcodes), that doesn't necessarily make those sites reliable. However, often if a publisher has gone to the trouble of supporting URLs for things, they will have taken other steps to ensure the data quality and reliability. You can see, for example, if the data has an open data certificate. Whether you consider the website reliable is a judgement call.</help>
					</question>
					<if test="this.reliableExternalUrls">
						<question id="externalUrls">
							<label>Does the data use those external URLs?</label>
							<yesno />
							<help>If there are URLs that resolve to reliable data for the things that you are describing in your data, you should reuse those URLs in your data. This reduces the duplication and enhances the ability for data from different sources to be brought together.</help>
							<requirement level="exemplar">You should use existing external URLs in your data so that it's easy to combine with other data that uses those URLs.</requirement>
						</question>
					</if>
				</if>
			</if>
		</group>
		<group id="trust">
			<label>Trust</label>
			<help>helping reusers to understand how much to trust the data</help>
			<question id="provenance">
				<label>Do you provide machine-readable provenance for the data?</label>
				<yesno />
				<help more="http://www.w3.org/TR/prov-primer/">The provenance of data is a trace of how it was created and processed prior to publication. This can help establish trust in the data that you are publishing by enabling reusers to trace back how the data has been handled.</help>
				<requirement level="exemplar">You should provide a machine-readable provenance trail for the data so that reusers can trace how it has been processed.</requirement>
			</question>
			<question id="digitalCertificate">
				<label>Where do you describe how reusers can verify the data they receive?</label>
				<input type="url" placeholder="Verification Process URL" />
				<help>If you are delivering important data, reusers should be able to verify that the data that they receive is the same as the data that you are publishing. For example, you might digitally sign the data that you publish, so that reusers can tell if it has been tampered with.</help>
				<requirement level="exemplar">You should describe how reusers can verify whether the data they receive is the same as that originally published by you, so that they know whether to trust it.</requirement>
			</question>
		</group>
	</group>
	<group id="social">
		<label>Social Information</label>
		<group id="documentation">
			<label>Documentation</label>
			<help>helping reusers to understand the context and content of the data</help>
			<if test="this.documentationUrl() !== ''">
				<question id="documentationMetadata">
					<label>Does your data documentation include machine-readable data for:</label>
					<!-- these are properties from DCAT -->
					<checkboxset>
						<option value="title">
							<label>title</label>
							<requirement level="pilot">You should include a title for the data in your documentation so that reusers know how to refer to it.</requirement>
						</option>
						<option value="description">
							<label>description</label>
							<requirement level="pilot">You should include a description of the data in your documentation so that reusers know what it contains.</requirement>
						</option>
						<option value="issued">
							<label>release date</label>
							<requirement level="pilot">You should include a release date in your documentation so that reusers know how current it is.</requirement>
						</option>
						<option value="modified">
							<label>modification date</label>
							<requirement level="standard">You should include the last modification date in your documentation so that reusers know whether the copy they have is up to date.</requirement>
						</option>
						<option value="accrualPeriodicity">
							<label>frequency of releases</label>
							<requirement level="standard">You should indicate in your documentation how frequently new versions of the data will be released so reusers can tell if it will be updated at all, and if so how frequently they will need to check it.</requirement>
						</option>
						<option value="identifier">
							<label>identifier</label>
							<requirement level="standard">You should include a canonical URL for the data in your documentation so that different reusers know how to point to it consistently.</requirement>
						</option>
						<option value="landingPage">
							<label>landing page</label>
							<requirement level="standard">You should include a canonical URL for the documentation itself in your documentation so that different reusers know how to point to it consistently.</requirement>
						</option>
						<option value="language">
							<label>language</label>
							<requirement level="standard">You should include the language of the data in your documentation so that reusers know whether they will be able to understand it.</requirement>
						</option>
						<option value="publisher">
							<label>publisher</label>
							<requirement level="standard">You should indicate the publisher of the data in your documentation as reusers may use this information to determine how much to trust the data.</requirement>
						</option>
						<option value="spatial">
							<label>spatial/geographical coverage</label>
							<requirement level="standard">You should include an indication of the geographic area the data covers in your documentation so that reusers understand what is included within it.</requirement>
						</option>
						<option value="temporal">
							<label>temporal coverage</label>
							<requirement level="standard">You should include the time period the data covers in your documentation so that reusers understand what is included within it.</requirement>
						</option>
						<option value="theme">
							<label>theme(s)</label>
							<requirement level="standard">You should include a general theme for the data in your documentation so that reusers know roughly what it's about.</requirement>
						</option>
						<option value="keyword">
							<label>keyword(s) or tag(s)</label>
							<requirement level="standard">You should include keywords or tags for the data in your documentation to help reusers to search for the data effectively.</requirement>
						</option>
						<option value="distribution">
							<label>distribution(s)</label>
						</option>
					</checkboxset>
				</question>
				<if test="this.documentationMetadata().distribution">
					<question id="distributionMetadata">
						<label>Does your documentation include machine-readable metadata for each distribution on:</label>
						<checkboxset>
							<option value="title">
								<label>title</label>
								<requirement level="pilot">You should include a title for each distribution within the documentation so reusers know how to refer to it.</requirement>
							</option>
							<option value="description">
								<label>description</label>
								<requirement level="pilot">You should include a description of each distribution within the documentation so reusers know what it contains.</requirement>
							</option>
							<option value="issued">
								<label>release date</label>
								<requirement level="pilot">You should include a release date for each distribution within the documentation so that reusers know how current it is.</requirement>
							</option>
							<option value="modified">
								<label>modification date</label>
								<requirement level="standard">You should include the last modification date for each distribution within the documentation so reusers know whether their copy of it is up to date.</requirement>
							</option>
							<option value="license">
								<label>licence</label>
								<requirement level="standard">You should include a reference to the licence or waiver that applies to each distribution within the documentation so reusers know what they can do with the data.</requirement>
							</option>
							<option value="accessURL">
								<label>URL for accessing the data</label>
								<help>This metadata should be used when the distribution is not a download (eg if it's a pointer to an API)</help>
							</option>
							<option value="downloadURL">
								<label>URL for downloading the dataset</label>
							</option>
							<option value="byteSize">
								<label>size in bytes</label>
							</option>
							<option value="mediaType">
								<label>media type of the download</label>
							</option>
						</checkboxset>
					</question>
				</if>
			</if>
			<if test="this.releaseType() === 'service'">
				<question id="serviceDocumentation">
					<label>Where is the documentation for the API?</label>
					<input type="url" />
					<requirement level="pilot">You should provide documentation about how the API works so that reusers can find out how to use it.</requirement>
				</question>
			</if>
			<question id="vocabulary">
				<label>Do the data formats use vocabularies?</label>
				<yesno required="standard" />
				<help>Formats such as JSON, XML or Turtle provide a generic syntax and need to be supplemented with a schema for developers to understand it.</help>
			</question>
			<if test="this.vocabulary() === 'true'">
				<question id="schemaDocumentationUrl">
					<label>Where is the documentation for the vocabularies?</label>
					<input type="url" />
					<requirement level="standard">You should provide documentation for any vocabulary you use within the data you publish so that reusers know how to interpret the data.</requirement>
				</question>
			</if>
			<question id="codelists">
				<label>Are there any codes used within the data?</label>
				<yesno required="standard" />
				<help>Data often includes codes for things like geographical areas, spending categories or diseases; these codes need to be explained for reusers.</help>
			</question>
			<if test="this.codelists() === 'true'">
				<question id="codelistDocumentationUrl">
					<label>Where are the codes documented?</label>
					<input type="url" />
					<requirement level="standard">You should provide documentation for the codes used within your data so that reusers know how to interpret the data.</requirement>
				</question>
			</if>
		</group>
		<group id="support">
			<label>Support</label>
			<help>giving reusers contact with people who can help them</help>
			<question id="contactEmail">
				<label>What's the contact email address for questions about this data?</label>
				<input type="email" placeholder="Contact Email Address"/>
				<help>Provide an email address that people can contact with queries about the data.</help>
				<requirement level="pilot">You should have a contact email address so that people can get in touch with you about any questions about the data.</requirement>
			</question>
			<question id="forum">
				<label>Where do you recommend people discuss this dataset?</label>
				<input type="url" placeholder="Forum or Mailing List URL"/>
				<help>Provide a URL for the forum or mailing list where developers using this dataset should discuss it.</help>
				<requirement level="standard">You should indicate a place where people using this dataset should discuss the data so that they can support each other.</requirement>
			</question>
			<if test="this.corrected() === 'true'">
				<question id="correctionReporting">
					<label>Where do you describe how to provide corrections?</label>
					<input type="url" placeholder="Correction Instructions URL" />
					<help>Provide a link to a page that describes how people should provide corrections if they discover errors in  the data.</help>
					<requirement level="standard">You should provide instructions for people who discover errors in the data so that they know how to report them.</requirement>
				</question>
				<question id="correctionDiscovery">
					<label>Where do you describe how to learn about corrections?</label>
					<input type="url" placeholder="Correction Notification URL" />
					<help>Provide a link to a page that describes how corrections will be communicated to reusers of the data.</help>
					<requirement level="standard">You should provide an announcement mailing list or a feed to which reusers can subscribe to learn of corrections to the data so that they can keep their local copies up to date.</requirement>
				</question>
			</if>
			<if test="this.dataPersonal() === 'personal' || this.dataPersonal() === 'possibly'">
				<question id="dataProtectionEmail">
					<label>What's the contact email address for confidentiality concerns?</label>
					<input type="email" placeholder="Confidentiality Contact Email Address" />
					<requirement level="pilot">You should provide a contact email address so that reusers with concerns about disclosure of personal details within the data can get in touch.</requirement>
				</question>
			</if>
		</group>
		<group id="services">
			<label>Services</label>
			<help>providing reusers with tools to help work with the data</help>
			<question id="libraries">
				<label>Where do you list tools for working with the data?</label>
				<input type="url" placeholder="Tool URL"/>
				<help>Provide a link to a page that lists the tools that people and developers can use when working with the data.</help>
				<requirement level="exemplar">You should provide a list of software libraries and other tools that help developers who want to work with the data so that reusers can find and reuse them rather than building them from scratch.</requirement>
			</question>
		</group>
	</group>
	<certificate>		
		<p class="alert">This certificate has been awarded based on the answers provided by <placeholder ref="publisher">its curator</placeholder>. The awarded level is based on the assumption that these answers are accurate. The answers have not been audited by the Open Data Institute.</p>
		<section>
			<h2>Legal Information</h2>
			<if test="this.publisherRights() === 'yes'">
				<p>
					<placeholder ref="publisher" /> has asserted they have the right to publish the data as open data
					<if test="this.publisherOrigin() === 'true'">and that they originally created or gathered all the data.</if>
					<if test="this.publisherOrigin() === 'false'">
						but that they did not originally create or gather all of it.
					</if>
				</p>
			</if>
			<if test="this.publisherRights() === 'unsure'">
				<p>
					<placeholder ref="publisher" /> has the right to publish the data
					<if test="this.publisherOrigin() === 'true'"> as open data because they originally created or gathered it.</if>
					<if test="this.publisherOrigin() === 'false'">
						as open data.
						<if test="this.thirdPartyOrigin() === 'true'">
							Some of the data was extracted or calculated from other data, but 
						</if>
					</if>
				</p>
			</if>
			<if test="this.sourceDocumentationUrl() !== ''">
				<p>
					<strong>Further Documentation:</strong>
					<a data-bind="attr: { href: sourceDocumentationUrl }">description of the sources of this data</a>
					<if test="this.sourceDocumentationMetadata() === 'true'">
						<small>includes machine-readable metadata</small>
					</if>
				</p>
			</if>
		</section>
		<!--
	<group id="legal">
		<label>Legal Information</label>
		<group id="ownership">
			<label>Rights</label>
			<help>ensuring that you have the right to publish the data</help>
			<if test="this.publisherRights() === 'yes' || this.publisherRights() === 'unsure'">
				<question id="publisherOrigin">
					<label>Was <em>all</em> this data originally created or gathered by you?</label>
					<yesno required="required" />
					<help>If not all the data was originally created or gathered by you then you might not have the right to republish it. Answer 'no' to this question if the data includes information that was sourced from outside your organisation, or if it includes data that other individuals or organisations have contributed. We ask this question to work out whether we have to ask about other organisations or people who might own some of the data.</help>
				</question>
			</if>
			<if test="this.publisherRights() === 'unsure'">
				<if test="this.publisherOrigin() === 'false'">
					<question id="thirdPartyOrigin">
						<label>Was some of this data extracted or calculated from other data?</label>
						<yesno required="required" />
						<help>You might have extracted data from another dataset, for example through an online service. Or you might have downloaded someone else's dataset and analysed it to create the data. In both these cases, we need to check that there are no legal barriers to you republishing the results of this data.</help>
						<if test="this.crowdsourced() === 'false'">
							<requirement test="this.thirdPartyOrigin() === 'true'">You have said that the data wasn't originally created or gathered by you, and wasn't crowd-sourced, so it must have been extracted or calculated from other data sources.</requirement>
						</if>
					</question>
					<if test="this.thirdPartyOrigin() === 'true'">
						<question id="thirdPartyOpen">
							<label>Are <em>all</em> the other data sources published as open data by their owners?</label>
							<yesno required="required" />
							<help>Open data is data that has been published under an open data licence or where the rights over that data have expired or been waived. If your data is created based on other data that is published as open data, then you can republish it. If your data incorporates data that is not published as open data, you will need to get legal advice to ensure that you can reuse that data and republish the results.</help>
							<if test="this.thirdPartyOpen() === 'false'">
								<requirement>You should get legal advice to ensure that you have the right to republish this data.</requirement>
							</if>
						</question>
					</if>
					<question id="crowdsourced">
						<label>Was some of this data crowd-sourced?</label>
						<yesno required="required" />
						<help>Crowd-sourcing involves collating data that is contributed by people operating outside your organisation. We ask about crowd-sourcing because if the data includes information that was contributed by others, you need to ensure that they granted their permission to publish their contributions as open data.</help>
						<if test="this.thirdPartyOrigin() === 'false'">
							<requirement test="this.crowdsourced() === 'true'">You have said that the data wasn't originally created or gathered by you, and wasn't extracted or calculated from other data, so it must have been crowd-sourced.</requirement>
						</if>
					</question>
					<if test="this.crowdsourced() === 'true'">
						<question id="crowdsourcedContent">
							<label>Did contributions require judgement?</label>
							<yesno required="required" />
							<help>The individuals who contributed to your data may have needed to employ their creativity or judgement to make their contributions. For example, writing a description or choosing whether or not to include some data in a dataset would require judgement. If judgement is involved, the contributors will have copyright over their contributions, so we will then need to check that they have transferred or waived their rights, or licensed the data, to you.</help>
						</question>
						<if test="this.crowdsourcedContent() === 'true'">
							<question id="claUrl">
								<label>Where is the Contributor Licence Agreement (CLA)?</label>
								<input type="url" placeholder="Contributor Licence Agreement URL" required="required" />
								<help more="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Contributor_License_Agreement">A Contributor Licence Agreement is an agreement with contributors that ensures that you can reuse the data that they contribute. It will either transfer the rights in the contributions to you, waive their rights, or license the data to you such that you can republish it.</help>
							</question>
							<question id="cldsRecorded">
								<label>Have all contributors agreed to the CLA?</label>
								<yesno required="required" />
								<help>All contributors need to agree to a Contributor Licence Agreement (CLA) so that you can reuse or republish their contributions. You should keep a record of who has provided contributions and whether or not they have agreed to the CLA.</help>
								<requirement>You must obtain agreement to a Contributor Licence Agreement from the contributors to your data to give you the right to republish their contributions as open data.</requirement>
							</question>
						</if>
					</if>
				</if>
			</if>
			<if test="this.publisherOrigin() === 'false'">
				<question id="sourceDocumentationUrl">
					<label>Where do you describe the sources of the data?</label>
					<input type="url" placeholder="Data Sources Documentation URL" />
					<help>If not all the data was originally created or gathered by you then even if you have the rights to publish it, it is good practice to document where the data was sourced from (its provenance) and the rights under which you are publishing the data.</help>
					<requirement level="pilot">You should document where the data was sourced from and the rights under which you are publishing the data so reusers are assured that they can reuse the parts sourced from third parties.</requirement>
				</question>
				<if test="this.sourceDocumentationUrl() !== ''">
					<question id="sourceDocumentationMetadata">
						<label>Does the documentation about the sources of the data include machine-readable data?</label>
						<yesno />
						<help>The documentation about the sources of the data needs to be human-readable, so that reusers can work out what it says, but it also helps if it contains machine-readable metadata. This helps those people who publish open data to find out how their data is being used, which helps them to justify its ongoing publication.</help>
						<requirement level="standard">You should include machine-readable data about the sources of data that you're using.</requirement>
					</question>
				</if>
			</if>
		</group>
		<group id="licensing">
			<label>Licensing</label>
			<help>giving other people permission to reuse the data</help>
			<question id="copyrightURL">
				<label>Where is your copyright statement?</label>
				<input type="url" />
				<help>A copyright statement states who owns the copyright and database rights in the data, and it says what you are allowing reusers can do with that data, usually by indicating its licence. We are asking where it is to check that you have one, to point reusers to it, and so we can automatically find out more about the terms under which you're making the data available.</help>
				<requirement level="pilot">You should have a page that states your copyright over the data and provides details of any attribution that people should use so that reusers understand how they can reuse it.</requirement>
			</question>
			<if test="this.copyrightURL() !== ''">
				<question id="copyrightStatementMetadata">
					<label>Does your copyright statement include machine-readable data for:</label>
					<checkboxset>
						<option value="license">
							<label>licences</label>
							<requirement level="standard">You should provide machine-readable data in your copyright statement about the licences that should be used when the data is reused so that automated tools can flag the data as open data.</requirement>
						</option>
						<option value="attribution">
							<label>attribution</label>
							<requirement level="exemplar">You should provide machine-readable data in your copyright statement about the attribution that should be used when the data is reused so that automated tools can use the information.</requirement>
						</option>
						<option value="attributionURL">
							<label>attribution URL</label>
							<requirement level="exemplar">You should provide machine-readable data in your copyright statement about the URL that should be linked to when the data is reused so that automated tools can use the information.</requirement>
						</option>
						<option value="morePermissions">
							<label>additional permissions or alternative licences</label>
						</option>
						<option value="useGuidelines">
							<label>non-binding use guidelines</label>
						</option>
					</checkboxset>
					<help more="http://labs.creativecommons.org/2011/ccrel-guide/">If you have a copyright statement, it is good to embed within it machine-readable information about the licence under which you are making your data available. We can use this to automatically fill in parts of this questionnaire. Others can use it to automatically create attribution statements when they reuse your data.</help>
				</question>
			</if>
			<question id="dataLicence">
				<label>Under which licence can others reuse the data?</label>
				<select required="required">
					<option/>
					<option value="odc-by">Open Data Commons Attribution License</option>
					<option value="odc-by-sa">Open Data Commons Open Database License (ODbL)</option>
					<option value="pddl">Open Data Commons Public Domain Dedication and Licence (PDDL)</option>
					<option value="cc0">Creative Commons CCZero</option>
					<option value="ogl">UK Open Government Licence</option>
					<option value="na">Not applicable</option>
					<option value="other">Other...</option>
				</select>
				<help>The creator of a database automatically gets database rights where they spend substantial effort gathering, verifying and presenting data. You need to have a waiver or a licence that covers the database rights in the data so reusers know that they can reuse it. The licences that are listed here are the ones that are most commonly used; if there are no database rights, they've expired, or you've waived them, choose 'Not applicable'. We ask about the licence because we want to make sure that the data is actually open for others to reuse from a legal perspective.</help>
			</question>
			<if test="this.dataLicence() === 'na'">
				<question id="dataNotApplicable">
					<label>Why is a licence not applicable for this data?</label>
					<radioset required="required">
						<option value="norights">
							<label>there is no database right in this data</label>
							<help>You only have a database right in this data if you have spent substantial effort gathering, verifying or presenting the data. It's possible that there's no database right in the data, for example if the data is created from scratch, presented in an obvious way, and not checked against anything.</help>
						</option>
						<option value="expired">
							<label>the applicable database rights have expired</label>
							<help>Database rights last for ten years. If the data was last changed more than ten years ago, then the database rights within it will have expired.</help>
						</option>
						<option value="waived">
							<label>the applicable database rights have been waived</label>
							<help>You can waive your database rights, which means that no one owns them and anyone can do whatever they want with the data.</help>
						</option>
					</radioset>
				</question>
				<if test="this.dataNotApplicable() === 'waived'">
					<question id="dataWaiver">
						<label>Which waiver are you using to waive database rights?</label>
						<select required="required">
							<option/>
							<option value="pddl">Open Data Commons Public Domain Dedication and Licence (PDDL)</option>
							<option value="cc0">Creative Commons CCZero</option>
							<option value="other">Other...</option>
						</select>
						<help>If you waive your database right, you need to have a statement that says that you've done so, so that reusers know that they can do whatever they like with the data. There are existing waivers that you can use (PDDL and CCZero). You can author your own, but you should have legal advice if you do.</help>
					</question>
					<if test="this.dataWaiver() === 'other'">
						<question id="dataOtherWaiver">
							<label>Where is the waiver for the database rights?</label>
							<input type="url" required="required" placeholder="Waiver URL" />
							<help>If you have created your own waiver, we ask where it is so that we can check that it's publicly available and so that we can point reusers to it so they can check that it does in fact waive your database rights.</help>
						</question>
					</if>
				</if>
			</if>
			<if test="this.dataLicence() === 'other'">
				<question id="otherDataLicenceName">
					<label>What's the name of the licence?</label>
					<input required="required" />
					<help>If you are using another licence, we ask for its name so that we can refer to it within the Open Data Certificate.</help>
				</question>
				<question id="otherDataLicenceURL">
					<label>What's the location the licence?</label>
					<input type="url" required="required" />
					<help>If you are using another licence, we ask for a pointer to it so that we can link to it from within your Open Data Certificate and so that we can check that it is publicly accessible.</help>
				</question>
				<question id="otherDataLicenceOpen">
					<label>Is the licence an open licence?</label>
					<yesno required="required" />
					<help more="http://opendefinition.org/">The <a href="http://opendefinition.org/">Open Knowledge Definition</a> defines what an open data licence is and the <a href="">Open Definition Advisory Board</a> maintain a list of <a href="http://licenses.opendefinition.org/">open licences</a>. If the licence is not given in that list, it it is either not open or hasn't yet been assessed.</help>
					<requirement>You must publish open data under an open licence so that others can reuse it.</requirement>
				</question>
			</if>
			<question id="contentLicence">
				<label>Under which licence can others reuse the content?</label>
				<select required="required">
					<option/>
					<option value="cc-by">Creative Commons Attribution</option>
					<option value="cc-by-sa">Creative Commons Attribution Share-Alike</option>
					<option value="cc0">Creative Commons CCZero</option>
					<option value="ogl">UK Open Government Licence</option>
					<option value="na">Not applicable</option>
					<option value="other">Other...</option>
				</select>
				<help>The creator of content automatically gets copyright over that content when they spend intellectual effort creating it. Note that creative content does not include facts. You need to have a waiver or licence that covers the copyright in the data so reusers know that they can reuse it. The licences that are listed here are the ones that are most commonly used; if there is no copyright in the data, it's expired, or you've waived copyright, choose 'Not applicable'. We ask about the licence because we want to make sure that the data is actually open for others to reuse from a legal perspective.</help>
			</question>
			<if test="this.contentLicence() === 'na'">
				<question id="contentNotApplicable">
					<label>Why is a licence not applicable for this data?</label>
					<radioset required="required">
						<option value="norights">
							<label>there is no copyright in this data</label>
							<help>You only have a copyright in this data if you have spent creative intellectual effort creating it, for example by creating text that is included within the data, or exercising judgement in choosing whether particular data is included. It's possible that there's no copyright in the data, for example if it only contains facts with no judgement involved in selecting what to include.</help>
						</option>
						<option value="expired">
							<label>the applicable copyright has expired</label>
							<help>Copyright lasts for a fixed length of time, based on either a number of years after the death of its creator or the publication of the content. If the content was created or published a long time ago, the copyright may have expired.</help>
						</option>
						<option value="waived">
							<label>the applicable copyright has been waived</label>
							<help>You can waive your copyright, which means that no one owns it and anyone can do whatever they want with the data.</help>
						</option>
					</radioset>
				</question>
				<if test="this.contentNotApplicable() === 'waived'">
					<question id="contentWaiver">
						<label>Which waiver are you using to waive copyright?</label>
						<select required="required">
							<option/>
							<option value="cc0">Creative Commons CCZero</option>
							<option value="other">Other...</option>
						</select>
						<help>If you waive your copyright, you need to have a statement that says that you've done so, so that reusers know that they can do whatever they like with the data. You can use an existing waiver (CCZero) or you can author your own, but you should have legal advice if you do.</help>
					</question>
					<if test="this.contentWaiver() === 'other'">
						<question id="contentOtherWaiver">
							<label>Where is the waiver for the copyright?</label>
							<input type="url" required="required" placeholder="Waiver URL" />
							<help>If you have created your own waiver, we ask where it is so that we can check that it's publicly available and so that we can point reusers to it so they can check that it does in fact waive your copyright.</help>
						</question>
					</if>
				</if>
			</if>
			<if test="this.contentLicence() === 'other'">
				<question id="otherContentLicenceName">
					<label>What's the name of the licence?</label>
					<input required="required" placeholder="Licence Name" />
					<help>If you are using another licence, we ask for its name so that we can refer to it within the Open Data Certificate.</help>
				</question>
				<question id="otherContentLicenceURL">
					<label>What's the location the licence?</label>
					<input type="url" required="required" placeholder="Licence URL" />
					<help>If you are using another licence, we ask for a pointer to it so that we can link to it from within your Open Data Certificate and so that we can check that it is publicly accessible.</help>
				</question>
				<question id="otherContentLicenceOpen">
					<label>Is the licence an open licence?</label>
					<yesno required="required" />
					<help more="http://opendefinition.org/">The <a href="http://opendefinition.org/">Open Knowledge Definition</a> defines what an open data licence is and the <a href="">Open Definition Advisory Board</a> maintain a list of <a href="http://licenses.opendefinition.org/">open licences</a>. If the licence is not given in that list, it it is either not open or hasn't yet been assessed.</help>
					<requirement>You must publish open data under an open licence so that others can reuse it.</requirement>
				</question>
			</if>
		</group>
		<group id="privacy">
			<label>Privacy</label>
			<help>ensuring that you protect people's privacy</help>
			<question id="dataPersonal">
				<label>Could the source of this data be personal data under the Data Protection Act?</label>
				<radioset required="pilot">
					<option value="not-personal">
						<label>no, the data could never be personal data as it is not about people or their activity</label>
						<help>Data that is about the activity of people can be personal data if there's the potential for it to be combined with other data to identify individuals. For example, data about road traffic flows is about people's activity and could be combined with other information (about an individual's commuting patterns) to reveal information about that individual.</help>
					</option>
					<option value="personal">
						<label>yes, the source of this data is classified as personal data within your organisation</label>
						<help more="http://www.ico.org.uk/for_organisations/data_protection/the_guide/key_definitions">Personal data is data that relates to a living individual who can be identified from the data or from the data in combination with other information. If your organisation has other information that can be used to identify the individuals in the source of this data, then it must be classified as personal data within your organisation.</help>
					</option>
					<option value="possibly">
						<label>yes, the source of this data could be classified as personal data if held by other people who have access to additional information</label>
						<help more="http://www.ico.org.uk/for_organisations/data_protection/the_guide/key_definitions">Personal data is data that relates to a living individual who can be identified from the data or from the data in combination with other information. Even if your organisation doesn't have other information that could be used to identify the individuals in the source of this data, it may be that other people do have access to such information.</help>
					</option>
				</radioset>
			</question>
			<if test="this.dataPersonal() === 'personal' || this.dataPersonal() === 'possibly'">
				<question id="consentExempt">
					<label>Is this data exempt from the non-disclosure provisions of the Data Protection Act?</label>
					<yesno required="pilot" />
					<help more="http://www.ico.org.uk/for_organisations/data_protection/the_guide/exemptions">There are exemptions from the non-disclosure provisions of the Data Protection Act, which mean that organisations do not have to comply with the normal non-disclosure provisions.</help>
				</question>
				<if test="this.consentExempt() === 'false'">
					<question id="privacyImpactAssessmentUrl">
						<label>Where is your privacy impact assessment published?</label>
						<input type="url" placeholder="Privacy Impact Assessment URL"/>
						<help more="http://www.ico.gov.uk/for_organisations/data_protection/topic_guides/privacy_impact_assessment.aspx">A <a href="http://www.ico.gov.uk/for_organisations/data_protection/topic_guides/privacy_impact_assessment.aspx">Privacy Impact Assessment</a> is a process for identifying privacy risks to individuals in the collection, use and disclosure of information. We ask where it is published because this enables us to check that it exists.</help>
						<requirement level="pilot">You should carry out a a privacy impact assessment to identify risks of releasing the data, mitigations against those risks, and to put in place processes that ensure that any breaches are handled effectively.</requirement>
					</question>
					<if test="this.privacyImpactAssessmentUrl() !== ''">
						<question id="piaAudited">
							<label>Has your Privacy Impact Assessment been independently audited?</label>
							<yesno />
							<help>An independent audit of a privacy impact assessment will check that the assessment has been carried out correctly. We ask if it has been independently audited to assess the rigour of the privacy impact assessment.</help>
							<requirement level="standard">You should have your privacy impact assessment independently audited to ensure that it has been carried out correctly.</requirement>
						</question>
					</if>
					<question id="individualConsentURL">
						<label>Where is the privacy notice you provide to affected individuals published?</label>
						<input type="url" placeholder="Privacy Notice URL" />
						<help more="http://www.ico.org.uk/for_organisations/data_protection/the_guide/principle_2">Unless you are exempt from the non-disclosure provisions of the Data Protection Act, you are required to give individuals privacy notices when collecting data about them, which should specify the purposes for which that data will be used. We ask where these are because reusers need to be able to look at them so that they can stick within the confines of the Data Protection Act when they are handling the data.</help>
						<requirement level="pilot">You should inform potential reusers about the purposes of processing personal data which individuals were informed of, so that reusers can comply with the Data Protection Act and use the data consistently with that consent.</requirement>
					</question>
					<question id="personalDataAnonymisation">
						<label>Has your anonymisation approach been audited?</label>
						<yesno />
						<help>An audit of your anonymisation approach will ensure that you have carried out the appropriate anonymisation technique for your data, and carried it out effectively. This can be done by a specialist within your organisation or an independent third party.</help>
						<requirement level="pilot">You should engage an expert to audit your anonymisation approach to ensure that it is appropriate for your data.</requirement>
					</question>
				</if>
				<if test="this.consentExempt() === 'true'">
					<question id="privacyImpactAssessment">
						<label>Have you carried out a privacy impact assessment?</label>
						<yesno />
						<help more="http://www.ico.gov.uk/for_organisations/data_protection/topic_guides/privacy_impact_assessment.aspx">A <a href="http://www.ico.gov.uk/for_organisations/data_protection/topic_guides/privacy_impact_assessment.aspx">Privacy Impact Assessment</a> is a process for identifying privacy risks to individuals in the collection, use and disclosure of information. Even if you are exempt from the non-disclosure provisions of the Data Protection Act, you should carry out a privacy impact assessment so that you are aware of the possible risks of making the data open. We do not expect you to publish this privacy impact assessment because it might contain sensitive information about the risks that you are prepared to take.</help>
						<requirement level="standard">You should carry out a a privacy impact assessment to identify risks of releasing the data, mitigations against those risks, and to put in place processes that ensure that any breaches are handled effectively.</requirement>
					</question>
				</if>
			</if>
		</group>
	</group>
		<section>
			<h2>Practical Information</h2>
			<if test="this.releaseType() === 'oneoff'">
				<p>It is a one-off release of a single dataset.</p>
			</if>
			<if test="this.releaseType() === 'collection'">
				<p>It is a one-off release of a collection of related datasets.</p>
			</if>
			<if test="this.releaseType() === 'series'">
				<p>The data is released as a series of related datasets.</p>
			</if>
			<if test="this.releaseType() === 'series'">
				<p>The data can be accessed through an API.</p>
			</if>
		</section>
		<section>
			<h2>Technical Information</h2>
		</section>
		<section>
			<h2>Support Information</h2>
			<if test="this.documentationUrl() !== ''">
				<p>See <placeholder ref="documentationUrl" /> for more information.</p>
			</if>
		</section>
		<group id="practical">
		<label>Practical Information</label>
		<group id="findability">
			<label>Findability</label>
			<help>helping reusers to locate the data</help>
			<question id="linkedTo">
				<label>Is documentation about the data findable within three clicks of your organisation's home page?</label>
				<yesno />
				<help>The documentation about the data that should be findable is the page that you have given as the Documentation URL. This should be findable by clicking on links from the home page of your organisation (not through searching).</help>
				<requirement level="standard">You should ensure that reusers can easily find your data from your organisation's home page.</requirement>
			</question>
			<question id="listed">
				<label>Is the data listed somewhere, alongside data from the wider sector?</label>
				<yesno />
				<help>You can make your data easier to find by making sure that it is listed within relevant data catalogs and by ensuring it turns up in relevant search results.</help>
				<requirement level="standard">You should ensure that reusers can locate your data through searching for it in locations that list available data.</requirement>
			</question>
			<if test="this.listed() === 'true'">
				<repeat id="listings">
					<label>Listing</label>
					<question id="listing">
						<label>Where is the data listed?</label>
						<input type="url" required="required" placeholder="Listing URL" />
						<help>Give a URL that leads to a listing of this data alongside data from the wider sector.  For example, give a URL for a search that includes this data's listing on data.gov.uk (if it's UK public sector data), hub.data.ac.uk (if it's UK academia data), MEDIN (if it's marine data), or the URL of a search on Google or Bing.</help>
					</question>
				</repeat>
			</if>
		</group>
		<group id="accuracy">
			<label>Accuracy</label>
			<help>providing assurance that the data is up to date</help>
			<if test="this.releaseType() === 'service'">
				<question id="serviceType">
					<label>Does the data underlying the API change over time?</label>
					<radioset required="pilot">
						<option value="static">
							<label>no, the API simply provides easy access to unchanging data</label>
							<help>Some APIs are created by processing a single unchanging dataset: the purpose of the API is to make accessing this data easier, particularly when there is lots of that data.</help>
						</option>
						<option value="changing">
							<label>yes, the API provides instant access to changing data</label>
							<help>Some APIs are created over changeable data, and the primary purpose of the API is to provide up-to-date access to this data.</help>
						</option>
					</radioset>
				</question>
			</if>
			<if test="this.releaseType() === 'oneoff' || this.releaseType() === 'collection' || (this.releaseType() === 'service' &amp;&amp; this.serviceType() === 'static')">
				<question id="timeSensitive">
					<label>Will this data go out of date?</label>
					<radioset>
						<option value="true">
							<label>yes, this data will go out of date over time</label>
							<help>For example, a dataaset that contains the current location of bus stops will go out of date over time, as some bus stops are moved or new bus stops created.</help>
						</option>
						<option value="timestamped">
							<label>yes, this data will go out of date over time but the data is timestamped</label>
							<help>For example, demography statistics usually include a timestamp to indicate the time at which the statistics were relevant.</help>
							<requirement level="pilot">You should include timestamps in your data when releasing data that will go out of date over time, so that reusers know the time period it relates to.</requirement>
						</option>
						<option value="false">
							<label>no, this data does not contain any time-sensitive information</label>
							<help>For example, a dataset that contains the results of an experiment will not go out of date because the data accurately reports the results of the experiment.</help>
							<requirement level="standard">You should publish updates to data that goes out of date so that the information you provide does not go stale.</requirement>
						</option>
					</radioset>
				</question>
			</if>
			<if test="this.releaseType() === 'series'">
				<question id="frequentChanges">
					<label>Does the data you capture change on at least a daily basis?</label>
					<yesno required="pilot" />
					<help>Indicate whether you create or gather new data continuously, such that the underlying data changes most days. We ask about this because when data changes frequently it also goes out of date quickly, so we need to check that the releases that you are making are also made quickly and frequently.</help>
				</question>			
				<if test="this.frequentChanges() === 'true'">
					<question id="seriesType">
						<label>What type of dataset series is this?</label>
						<radioset required="exemplar">
							<option value="dumps">
								<label>regular copies of the complete database</label>
								<help>Select this option if you are publishing copies of the contents of your database at regular intervals. For example, you would choose this option if you had a database of bus stops and created a new, updated, version of that dataset every day. We ask this because when you are creating database dumps, it is often useful for reusers to be able to access a feed of the changes to the database so that they can keep their copies up to date.</help>
							</option>
							<option value="aggregate">
								<label>regular aggregates of changing data</label>
								<help>Select this option if you are creating new datasets at regular intervals. This might be because you are creating aggregates because the underlying data cannot be released as open data. Or it might be that you only publish the data that is new since the last publication.</help>
							</option>
						</radioset>
					</question>
					<if test="this.seriesType() === 'dumps'">
						<question id="changeFeed">
							<label>Is a feed of changes made available?</label>
							<yesno />
							<help>Indicate whether you make available a feed of the changes that occur to the data that you capture, such as new entries or amendments to existing entries. A feed might be in a format such as RSS or Atom, or a custom data format.</help>
							<requirement level="exemplar">You should provide a feed of changes in your data so that it's easy for reusers to keep their copies up to date.</requirement>
						</question>
					</if>
					<question id="frequentSeriesPublication">
						<label>How frequently do you create a new release?</label>
						<radioset>
							<option value="rarely">
								<label>less frequently than once a month</label>
							</option>
							<option value="monthly">
								<label>at least every month</label>
								<requirement level="pilot">You should create a new dataset release every month so that reusers can access up-to-date information.</requirement>
							</option>
							<option value="weekly">
								<label>at least every week</label>
								<requirement level="standard">You should create a new dataset release every week so that reusers can access up-to-date information.</requirement>
							</option>
							<option value="daily">
								<label>at least every day</label>
								<requirement level="exemplar">You should create a new dataset release every day so that reusers can access up-to-date information.</requirement>
							</option>
						</radioset>
						<help>We ask about the frequency with which you publish new datasets in the series because this determines how out of date the data that you are making available will get before reusers can get an update to their data.</help>
					</question>
				</if>
				<question id="seriesPublicationDelay">
					<label>What is the delay between creating a dataset and publishing it?</label>
					<radioset>
						<option value="extreme">
							<label>longer than the gap between releases</label>
							<help>For example, if you are creating a new version of the dataset every day, then choose this option if it takes more than a day for the dataset to then be published.</help>
						</option>
						<option value="reasonable">
							<label>about the same as the gap between releases</label>
							<help>For example, if you are creating a new version of the dataset every day, then choose this option if it takes about a day for the dataset to then be published.</help>
							<requirement level="pilot">You should have a delay between creating and publishing a dataset that is less than the gap between releases so that reusers can access up-to-date information.</requirement>
						</option>
						<option value="good">
							<label>less than half the gap between releases</label>
							<help>For example, if you are creating a new version of the dataset every day, then choose this option if it takes less than twelve hours for the data to then be published.</help>
							<requirement level="standard">You should have a delay between creating and publishing a dataset that is less than half the gap between releases so that reusers can access up-to-date information.</requirement>
						</option>
						<option value="minimal">
							<label>there is minimal or no delay</label>
							<help>Choose this option if the delay is in the order of a few seconds if the datasets are created frequently, or a few minutes if they are made less frequently.</help>
							<requirement level="exemplar">You should have minimal or no delay between creating and publishing datasets so that reusers can access up-to-date information.</requirement>
						</option>
					</radioset>
				</question>
			</if>
			<if test="this.releaseType() === 'service'">
				<question id="provideDumps">
					<label>Do you also provide dumps of the dataset?</label>
					<yesno />
					<help>A dump is an extract of the data into a static file that developers can download to get hold of the whole dataset. Being able to access a dump of the whole dataset enables different kinds of analyses than API access.</help>
					<requirement level="standard">You should enable reusers to download the entire dataset so that they can analyse it in its entirety.</requirement>
				</question>
				<if test="this.serviceType() === 'changing'">
					<if test="this.provideDumps() === 'true'">
						<question id="dumpFrequency">
							<label>How frequently do you create a new dump?</label>
							<radioset>
								<option value="rarely">
									<label>less frequently than once a month</label>
								</option>
								<option value="monthly">
									<label>at least every month</label>
									<requirement level="pilot">You should create a new database dump every month, so that new reusers can get hold of an up-to-date dump.</requirement>
								</option>
								<option value="weekly">
									<label>within a week of any change</label>
									<requirement level="standard">You should create a new database dump within a week of any change, so that new reusers do not have long to wait for an up-to-date dump.</requirement>
								</option>
								<option value="daily">
									<label>within a day of any change</label>
									<requirement level="exemplar">You should create a new database dump within a day of any change, so that new reusers can easily get hold of an up-to-date dump.</requirement>
								</option>
							</radioset>
							<help>Providing new database dumps within a short period ensures that new developers can get started with up-to-date data whenever they start looking at the data.</help>
						</question>
					</if>
				</if>
				<if test="this.timeSensitive() !== 'true'">
					<question id="corrected">
						<label>Will this data be corrected if it contains errors?</label>
						<yesno />
						<help>Indicate whether the data will be corrected in cases where errors are discovered within the data. We ask this because it is good practice to correct data that is revealed to contain errors (especially as you should be using this data yourself), and because if you do correct the data you need to provide additional support for reusers who will need to be informed of these corrections.</help>
						<requirement level="standard">You should correct data that is found to contain errors so that all users benefit from improvements in accuracy.</requirement>
					</question>
				</if>
			</if>
		</group>
		<group id="quality">
			<label>Quality</label>
			<help>helping reusers to understand where there might be problems in the data</help>
			<question id="qualityUrl">
				<label>Where are known issues with the quality of the data documented?</label>
				<input type="url" placeholder="Quality Issues URL" />
				<help>There are usually areas within any non-trivial data where there are known quality problems. For example, maybe the equipment that collected the data malfunctioned for a day, or the data was migrated between two systems and errors crept in during that migration. Documenting these helps reusers to have a better understanding of the data that they are using.</help>
				<requirement level="standard">You should document any known issues with the quality of the data so that reusers can understand how much they can rely on the data.</requirement>
			</question>
			<question id="qualityControlUrl">
				<label>Where is your quality control process described?</label>
				<input type="url" placeholder="Quality Control Process Description URL" />
				<help>A quality control process checks the quality of the data on an ongoing basis, either by hand or automatically, or through a combination of techniques. Having a publicly available description of your quality control process reassures reusers that you are checking the quality of the data that you are making available, and helps them to identify places that could be improved.</help>
				<requirement level="exemplar">You should document your quality control process so that reusers can understand how much they can rely on the data.</requirement>
			</question>
		</group>
		<group id="guarantees">
			<label>Guarantees</label>
			<help>helping reusers to understand how much to rely on the data</help>
			<if test="this.releaseType() === 'service'">
				<question id="serviceAvailability">
					<label>What is the guaranteed availability of the service?</label>
					<radioset>
						<option value="minimal">
							<label>there are minimal guarantees about the availability of the service</label>
						</option>
						<option value="99%">
							<label>at least 99% availability</label>
							<requirement level="pilot">You should guarantee at least 99% availability (less than 3.65 days downtime/year) of the service so that reusers know they can rely on it.</requirement>
						</option>
						<option value="99.9%">
							<label>at least 99.9% availability</label>
							<requirement level="standard">You should guarantee at least 99.9% availability (less than 8.76 hours downtime/year) of the service so that reusers know they can rely on it.</requirement>
						</option>
						<option value="99.999%">
							<label>at least 99.999% availability</label>
							<requirement level="exemplar">You should guarantee at least 99.999% availability (less than 5.26 minutes downtime/year) of the service so that reusers know they can rely on it.</requirement>
						</option>
					</radioset>
					<help>You will probably have in place a service-level agreement (SLA) with the service provider for the servers that you are using to host the data. These SLAs should indicate guaranteed up-time for the servers, and hence the availability of your data.</help>
				</question>
			</if>
			<question id="onGoingAvailability">
				<label>For how long will the data be available in this way?</label>
				<radioset>
					<option value="experimental">
						<label>this data may disappear at any time</label>
					</option>
					<option value="short">
						<label>this data is available experimentally but should be around for another year or so</label>
						<requirement level="pilot">You should provide a guarantee to reusers that the data will be available in this form for about a year so that they know they can rely on it.</requirement>
					</option>
					<option value="medium">
						<label>this data is included in your medium-term plans and should therefore be around for a couple of years</label>
						<requirement level="standard">You should provide a guarantee to reusers that the data will be available in this form in the medium term so that they know they can rely on it.</requirement>
					</option>
					<option value="long">
						<label>this data is part of your business-as-usual operation and will continue to be published long term</label>
						<requirement level="exemplar">You should provide a guarantee to reusers that the data will be available in this form long term so that they know they can rely on it.</requirement>
					</option>
				</radioset>
			</question>
		</group>
	</group>
	<group id="technical">
		<label>Technical Information</label>
		<if test="this.releaseType() !== ''">
			<group id="locations">
				<label>Locations</label>
				<help>helping reusers to access the data</help>
				<if test="this.releaseType() === 'oneoff'">
					<question id="datasetUrl">
						<label>What's the URL of the dataset?</label>
						<input type="url" placeholder="Dataset URL" />
						<help>This should be the URL of the dataset itself (for example a CSV file). This is a different URL from the page that describes the dataset. We ask this to ensure that the dataset is available on the web, and that it can be linked to directly, as this helps reusers to access the data.</help>
						<if test="this.documentationUrl() === ''">
							<requirement test="this.datasetUrl() !== ''">You must provide either a URL for the dataset or a URL for documentation about it so that reusers can find it.</requirement>
						</if>
						<if test="this.documentationUrl() !== ''">
							<requirement test="this.datasetUrl() !== ''" level="pilot">You should have a URL that is a direct link to the data itself so that reusers can access it easily.</requirement>
						</if>
					</question>
				</if>
				<if test="this.releaseType() === 'series'">
					<question id="versionManagement">
						<label>How do you publish the datasets in the series?</label>
						<checkboxset>
							<option value="current">
								<label>the data at a single "current" dataset URL is regularly updated</label>
								<help>Having a single "current" dataset URL means that there is one URL from which reusers can always download the most recent version of the dataset.</help>
								<requirement level="standard">You should have a single URL that can always be used to download the current version of the dataset so that reusers can access it easily.</requirement>
							</option>
							<option value="template">
								<label>the URLs for each release follow a regular pattern</label>
								<help>Having URLs that follow a regular pattern means publishing datsets at URLs where the date of publication is part of the URL itself. For example, if you published a dataset each month then you would include the month (eg <code>2013-04</code>) as part of the URL. This helps reusers to understand when the dataset dates from, and helps them write scripts that collect together all the published datasets or fetch new ones each time they're released.</help>
								<requirement level="pilot">You should use a regular pattern in the URLs for different releases so that reusers can easily get hold of each of those releases.</requirement>
							</option>
							<option value="list">
								<label>you publish a list of the releases</label>
								<help>Having a list of the releases means having a web page or a feed (such as Atom or RSS) that contains details of each release, including a link through to each individual release and a description of when it dates from. Reusers can use these lists to understand the frequency and regularity of your publication, and to help them write scripts that collect together all the published datasets or fetch new ones each time they're released.</help>
								<requirement level="standard">You should have a document or feed that provides a list of all the available releases so that reusers can create scripts to download all of them.</requirement>
							</option>
						</checkboxset>
						<if test="this.documentationUrl() === '' &amp;&amp; this.versionManagementStatus() !== 'complete'">
							<requirement>You must provide access to releases of your data through a current URL, a discoverable series of URLs or through a documentation page so that reusers can locate it.</requirement>
						</if>
					</question>
					<if test="this.versionManagement().current">
						<question id="currentDatasetUrl">
							<label>What's the URL of the current dataset?</label>
							<input type="url" placeholder="Current Dataset URL" required="required" />
							<help>This should be the single URL that always gives the current version of the dataset itself (for example a CSV file). The content at this URL should change each time a new version is released. This should not be a page describing the dataset.</help>
						</question>
					</if>
					<if test="this.versionManagement().template">
						<question id="versionsTemplateUrl">
							<label>What's the URL template for the releases?</label>
							<input type="url" placeholder="Version Template URL" required="required" />
							<help>This should be a template that outlines the structure of the URLs that are used when publishing different releases. Use <code>{<var>variable</var>}</code> within the URL template to indicate changeable parts of the URL. For example <code>http://example.com/data/monthly/mydata-{YY}{MM}.csv</code></help>
						</question>
					</if>
					<if test="this.versionManagement().list">
						<question id="versionsUrl">
							<label>What's the URL that gives a list of releases?</label>
							<input type="url" placeholder="Version List URL" required="required" />
							<help>This should be the URL of a page or feed that provides a machine-readable list of the previous versions of the dataset. If the list goes over several pages, then give the URL of the first page and make sure there are links to other pages.</help>
						</question>
					</if>
				</if>
				<if test="this.releaseType() === 'service'">
					<question id="endpointUrl">
						<label>What's the endpoint for the API?</label>
						<input type="url" placeholder="Endpoint URL" />
						<help>This should be a URL that provides a starting point for scripts that access the API. If the API supports it, this should be a service description document, which enables the script to work out the kinds of services that are offered by the API.</help>
						<if test="this.documentationUrl() === ''">
							<requirement test="this.endpointUrl() !== ''">You must provide either a URL for the API endpoint or a URL for the documentation about it so that reusers can find it.</requirement>
						</if>
						<if test="this.documentationUrl() !== ''">
							<requirement test="this.endpointUrl() !== ''" level="standard">You should have a service description document or similar single entry point for your API so that reusers can access it.</requirement>
						</if>
					</question>
					<if test="this.provideDumps() === 'true'">
						<question id="dumpManagement">
							<label>How do you publish the database dumps?</label>
							<checkboxset>
								<option value="current">
									<label>the data at a single "current" dump URL is regularly updated</label>
									<help>Having a single "current" dump URL means that there is one URL from which reusers can always download the most recently created dump.</help>
									<requirement level="standard">You should have a single URL that can always be used to download the current dump of the database so that reusers can find it.</requirement>
								</option>
								<option value="template">
									<label>the URLs for each release follow a regular pattern</label>
									<help>Having URLs that follow a regular pattern means publishing dumps at URLs where the date of publication is part of the URL itself. For example, if you published a dump each month then you would include the month (eg <code>2013-04</code>) as part of the URL. This helps reusers to understand when the dump dates from, and helps them write scripts that collect together all the published dumps (to carry out comparisons, for example) or fetch new ones each time they're released.</help>
									<requirement level="exemplar">You should use a regular pattern in the URLs for different dumps so that reusers can easily get hold of the dump for a particular time period.</requirement>
								</option>
								<option value="list">
									<label>you publish a list of the releases</label>
									<help>Having a list of the dumps means having a web page or a feed (such as Atom or RSS) that contains details of each dump, including a link through to each individual release and a description of when it dates from. Reusers can use these lists to understand the frequency and regularity of your publication, and to help them write scripts that collect together all the published datasets or fetch new ones each time they're released.</help>
									<requirement level="exemplar">You should have a document or feed that provides a list of all the available dumps so that reusers can create scripts to download all of them.</requirement>
								</option>
							</checkboxset>
						</question>
						<if test="this.dumpManagement().current">
							<question id="currentDumpUrl">
								<label>What's the URL of the current dump?</label>
								<input type="url" placeholder="Current Dump URL" required="required" />
								<help>This should be the URL that always gives the most recent dump of the database itself (for example as a CSV file). The content at this URL should change each time a new dump is created.</help>
							</question>
						</if>
						<if test="this.dumpManagement().template">
							<question id="dumpsTemplateUrl">
								<label>What's the URL template for the dumps?</label>
								<input type="url" placeholder="Dump Template URL" required="required" />
								<help>This should be a template that outlines the structure of the URLs that are used when publishing different dumps. Use <code>{<var>variable</var>}</code> within the URL template to indicate changeable parts of the URL. For example <code>http://example.com/data/monthly/mydata-{YY}{MM}.csv</code></help>
							</question>
						</if>
						<if test="this.dumpManagement().list">
							<question id="dumpsUrl">
								<label>What's the URL that gives a list of available dumps?</label>
								<input type="url" placeholder="Dump List URL" required="required" />
								<help>Enter the URL of a page or feed that provides a machine-readable list of the available dumps of the database.</help>
							</question>
						</if>
					</if>
				</if>
				<if test="this.changeFeed() === 'true'">
					<question id="changeFeedUrl">
						<label>What's the URL that provides a feed of changes?</label>
						<input type="url" placeholder="Change Feed URL" required="required" />
						<help>This should be the URL of a page or feed that provides a machine-readable list of the previous versions of the dataset. If the list goes over several pages, then give the URL of the first page and make sure there are links to other pages.</help>
					</question>
				</if>
			</group>
		</if>
		<group id="format">
			<label>Formats</label>
			<help>helping reusers to work with the data</help>
			<question id="machineReadable">
				<label>Is the data machine-readable?</label>
				<yesno />
				<help>A machine-readable format is one in which the information can be easily extracted from the data by a computer. For example, scanned photocopies of spreadsheets would not be machine-readable, but a CSV file would be.</help>
				<requirement level="pilot">You should provide the data in a machine-readable format so that it's easy to reuse.</requirement>
			</question>
			<question id="openStandard">
				<label>Is the data in an open standard format?</label>
				<yesno />
				<help more="https://www.gov.uk/government/uploads/system/uploads/attachment_data/file/183962/Open-Standards-Principles-FINAL.pdf">An open standard is one that is written through a defined fair, transparent and collaborative process and that anyone can implement. For example, XML, CSV and JSON are open standards.</help>
				<requirement level="standard">You should provide the data in an open standard format so that reusers can use common tools to process it.</requirement>
			</question>
			<question id="dataType">
				<label>What kind of data are you publishing?</label>
				<checkboxset required="pilot">
					<option value="documents">
						<label>human-readable documents</label>
						<help>Human-readable documents are those that are intended for human consumption. Examples would be policy documents, white papers, reports, meeting minutes and so on. These will usually have some structure to them, but the majority of the information within them is text.</help>
					</option>
					<option value="statistical">
						<label>statistical data, such as counts, averages and percentages</label>
						<help>Statistical data includes numeric data such as counts, averages or percentages. Examples would be census results, traffic flow information or crime statistics.</help>
					</option>
					<option value="geographic">
						<label>geographic information, such as points and boundaries</label>
						<help>Geographic information is any data that can be plotted on a map. These may be points or boundaries or lines.</help>
					</option>
					<option value="structured">
						<label>other kinds of structured data</label>
						<help>Other kinds of structured data would include things like event details, railway timetables, contact information: anything that can be interpreted as data, analysed and presented in multiple ways.</help>
					</option>
				</checkboxset>
			</question>
			<if test="this.dataType().documents">
				<question id="documentFormat">
					<label>Do the formats used for documents include:</label>
					<radioset>
						<option value="semantic">
							<label>one that exposes the semantic structure of documents, such as HTML, Docbook or Markdown</label>
							<help>Documents are typically structured into chapters or sections, with headings and tables, lists and figures, terms and their definitions. Formats such as HTML, Docbook and Markdown that label these structures make it easy to automatically create summaries such as tables of contents and glossaries, and make it easy to apply different styling to the document to make it appear differently.</help>
							<requirement level="standard">You should publish documents in a format that exposes their semantic structure so that it's easy to display in different styles.</requirement>
						</option>
						<option value="format">
							<label>one that focuses on the format of documents, such as OOXML or PDF</label>
							<help>Because documents are made for human consumption, they are typically created with great emphasis on how the document looks. Formats such as OOXML and PDF emphasise appearance: the use of particular fonts and colours and the positioning of different elements within the page. These are good for human consumption, but (despite being machine-readable) aren't as easy for machines to process or re-style.</help>
							<requirement level="pilot">You should publish documents in a format that is designed for documents so that it's easy to process.</requirement>
						</option>
						<option value="unsuitable">
							<label>only those not designed for documents, such as Excel, JSON or CSV</label>
							<help>Formats such as Excel or CSV are suited to tabular data. Formats such as JSON are suited for structured data. Because of the way they are structured, documents aren't suited to these formats.</help>
						</option>
					</radioset>
				</question>
			</if>
			<if test="this.dataType().statistical">
				<question id="statisticalFormat">
					<label>Do the formats used for statistical data include:</label>
					<radioset>
						<option value="statistical">
							<label>one that exposes the structure of the statistical hypercube data, such as SDMX or Data Cube</label>
							<help>Statistical data typically fits into a hypercube in which individual observations are related to a particular measure and a set of dimensions. Each observation may also be related to a number of annotations that provide additional context. Formats such as <a href="http://sdmx.org/">SDMX</a> and <a href="http://www.w3.org/TR/vocab-data-cube/">Data Cube</a> are designed to express this underlying structure of statistical data.</help>
							<requirement level="exemplar">You should publish statistical data in a format that exposes its dimensions and measures so that it's easy to analyse.</requirement>
						</option>
						<option value="tabular">
							<label>one that treats the statistical data as a table, such as CSV</label>
							<help>Statistical data can be arranged within a table of rows and columns. This lacks the expressiveness about the underlying hypercube, but is easy to process.</help>
							<requirement level="standard">You should publish tabular data in a format that exposes the tables of data so that it's easy to analyse.</requirement>
						</option>
						<option value="format">
							<label>one that focuses on the format of tabular data, such as Excel</label>
							<help>Excel and other spreadsheet formats typically emphasise the appearance of data, using italic or bold text, or indentation within fields, or the width of lines between rows, to indicate its underlying structure. This styling helps humans to understand the meaning of the data, but is hard for computers to interpret, and thus makes the data less reusable than it might otherwise be.</help>
							<requirement level="pilot">You should publish tabular data in a format that is designed for tabular data so that it's easy to process.</requirement>
						</option>
						<option value="unsuitable">
							<label>only those not designed for statistical or tabular data, such as Word or PDF</label>
							<help>Formats that are oriented towards human-readable documents, such as Word or PDF, are not suitable for statistical data, as they completely obscure the underlying structure of the data.</help>
						</option>
					</radioset>
				</question>
			</if>
			<if test="this.dataType().geographic">
				<question id="geographicFormat">
					<label>Do the formats used for geographic data include:</label>
					<radioset>
						<option value="specific">
							<label>one designed for geographic data, such as KML or GeoJSON</label>
							<help>Geographic data describes points, lines and boundaries. Formats that are designed for geographic data expose these kinds of structures in the data, which makes it easier to process automatically.</help>
							<requirement level="standard">You should publish geographic data in a format designed for geographic data so that it's easy to use with existing tools.</requirement>
						</option>
						<option value="generic">
							<label>a generic structured data format, such as JSON, XML or CSV</label>
							<help>Geographic data can be expressed using any format that can be used for normal structured data, particularly if it only holds data about points.</help>
							<requirement level="pilot">You should publish geographic data as structured data so that it's easy to process.</requirement>
						</option>
						<option value="unsuitable">
							<label>only those not designed for geographic data, such as Word or PDF</label>
							<help>Formats that are oriented towards human-readable documents, such as Word or PDF, are not suitable for geographic data, as they completely obscure the underlying structure of the data.</help>
						</option>
					</radioset>
				</question>
			</if>
			<if test="this.dataType().structured">
				<question id="structuredFormat">
					<label>Do the formats used for structured data include:</label>
					<radioset>
						<option value="suitable">
							<label>one designed for structured data, such as JSON, XML, Turtle or CSV</label>
							<help>Structured data formats break down data into a basic structure of things which have values for a known set of properties. These predictable formats are easy for machines to process.</help>
							<requirement level="pilot">You should publish structured data in a format designed for structured data so that it's easy to process.</requirement>
						</option>
						<option value="unsuitable">
							<label>only those not designed for structured data, such as Word or PDF</label>
							<help>Formats that are oriented towards human-readable documents, such as Word or PDF, are not suitable for structured data, as they completely obscure its underlying structure.</help>
						</option>
					</radioset>
				</question>
			</if>
			<question id="identifiers">
				<label>Are you using URLs to identify things in the data?</label>
				<yesno />
				<help>Data is usually about things, often things in the real world such as schools and roads. Identifying these things using URLs provides a mechanism for people to find out more about the thing that is being described by the data. If data from different sources consistently uses the same URL to refer to the same thing, those different data sources can be combined easily, to create more useful data. URLs can usefully be used in place of identifying numbers or codes.</help>
				<requirement level="standard">You should use URLs to identify things in the data, so that they can be easily referenced and combined with other data about those things.</requirement>
			</question>
			<if test="this.identifiers() === 'true'">
				<question id="resolvingUrls">
					<label>Do the URLs resolve to information about those things?</label>
					<yesno />
					<help>A URL that resolves to information about something is one that, when put in a browser, provides you with additional data. For example there are resolvable URLs for <a href="http://opencorporates.com/companies/gb/08030289">companies</a> and <a href="http://data.ordnancesurvey.co.uk/doc/postcodeunit/EC2A4JE">postcodes</a>. These provide human-readable pages but are also linked to underlying data which scripts can process.</help>
					<requirement level="exemplar">You should provide a page of information about each of the things in your data so that reusers can easily find and share that information.</requirement>
				</question>
				<question id="existingExternalUrls">
					<label>Do external URLs exist for any of those things?</label>
					<yesno required="exemplar" />
					<help>These may be other websites, outside your control, that provide URLs for the things that you are naming through URLs within your data. For example, your data might include postcodes, when there are URLs for postcodes that are supported on the Ordnance Survey website.</help>
				</question>
				<if test="this.existingExternalUrls() === 'true'">
					<question id="reliableExternalUrls">
						<label>Do those external URLs serve reliable data?</label>
						<yesno required="exemplar" />
						<help>Just because other websites support URLs for things (such as companies or postcodes), that doesn't necessarily make those sites reliable. However, often if a publisher has gone to the trouble of supporting URLs for things, they will have taken other steps to ensure the data quality and reliability. You can see, for example, if the data has an open data certificate. Whether you consider the website reliable is a judgement call.</help>
					</question>
					<if test="this.reliableExternalUrls">
						<question id="externalUrls">
							<label>Does the data use those external URLs?</label>
							<yesno />
							<help>If there are URLs that resolve to reliable data for the things that you are describing in your data, you should reuse those URLs in your data. This reduces the duplication and enhances the ability for data from different sources to be brought together.</help>
							<requirement level="exemplar">You should use existing external URLs in your data so that it's easy to combine with other data that uses those URLs.</requirement>
						</question>
					</if>
				</if>
			</if>
		</group>
		<group id="trust">
			<label>Trust</label>
			<help>helping reusers to understand how much to trust the data</help>
			<question id="provenance">
				<label>Do you provide machine-readable provenance for the data?</label>
				<yesno />
				<help more="http://www.w3.org/TR/prov-primer/">The provenance of data is a trace of how it was created and processed prior to publication. This can help establish trust in the data that you are publishing by enabling reusers to trace back how the data has been handled.</help>
				<requirement level="exemplar">You should provide a machine-readable provenance trail for the data so that reusers can trace how it has been processed.</requirement>
			</question>
			<question id="digitalCertificate">
				<label>Where do you describe how reusers can verify the data they receive?</label>
				<input type="url" placeholder="Verification Process URL" />
				<help>If you are delivering important data, reusers should be able to verify that the data that they receive is the same as the data that you are publishing. For example, you might digitally sign the data that you publish, so that reusers can tell if it has been tampered with.</help>
				<requirement level="exemplar">You should describe how reusers can verify whether the data they receive is the same as that originally published by you, so that they know whether to trust it.</requirement>
			</question>
		</group>
	</group>
	<group id="social">
		<label>Social Information</label>
		<group id="documentation">
			<label>Documentation</label>
			<help>helping reusers to understand the context and content of the data</help>
			<if test="this.documentationUrl() !== ''">
				<question id="documentationMetadata">
					<label>Does your data documentation include machine-readable data for:</label>
					<checkboxset>
						<option value="title">
							<label>title</label>
							<requirement level="pilot">You should include a title for the data in your documentation so that reusers know how to refer to it.</requirement>
						</option>
						<option value="description">
							<label>description</label>
							<requirement level="pilot">You should include a description of the data in your documentation so that reusers know what it contains.</requirement>
						</option>
						<option value="issued">
							<label>release date</label>
							<requirement level="pilot">You should include a release date in your documentation so that reusers know how current it is.</requirement>
						</option>
						<option value="modified">
							<label>modification date</label>
							<requirement level="standard">You should include the last modification date in your documentation so that reusers know whether the copy they have is up to date.</requirement>
						</option>
						<option value="accrualPeriodicity">
							<label>frequency of releases</label>
							<requirement level="standard">You should indicate in your documentation how frequently new versions of the data will be released so reusers can tell if it will be updated at all, and if so how frequently they will need to check it.</requirement>
						</option>
						<option value="identifier">
							<label>identifier</label>
							<requirement level="standard">You should include a canonical URL for the data in your documentation so that different reusers know how to point to it consistently.</requirement>
						</option>
						<option value="landingPage">
							<label>landing page</label>
							<requirement level="standard">You should include a canonical URL for the documentation itself in your documentation so that different reusers know how to point to it consistently.</requirement>
						</option>
						<option value="language">
							<label>language</label>
							<requirement level="standard">You should include the language of the data in your documentation so that reusers know whether they will be able to understand it.</requirement>
						</option>
						<option value="publisher">
							<label>publisher</label>
							<requirement level="standard">You should indicate the publisher of the data in your documentation as reusers may use this information to determine how much to trust the data.</requirement>
						</option>
						<option value="spatial">
							<label>spatial/geographical coverage</label>
							<requirement level="standard">You should include an indication of the geographic area the data covers in your documentation so that reusers understand what is included within it.</requirement>
						</option>
						<option value="temporal">
							<label>temporal coverage</label>
							<requirement level="standard">You should include the time period the data covers in your documentation so that reusers understand what is included within it.</requirement>
						</option>
						<option value="theme">
							<label>theme(s)</label>
							<requirement level="standard">You should include a general theme for the data in your documentation so that reusers know roughly what it's about.</requirement>
						</option>
						<option value="keyword">
							<label>keyword(s) or tag(s)</label>
							<requirement level="standard">You should include keywords or tags for the data in your documentation to help reusers to search for the data effectively.</requirement>
						</option>
						<option value="distribution">
							<label>distribution(s)</label>
						</option>
					</checkboxset>
				</question>
				<if test="this.documentationMetadata().distribution">
					<question id="distributionMetadata">
						<label>Does your documentation include machine-readable metadata for each distribution on:</label>
						<checkboxset>
							<option value="title">
								<label>title</label>
								<requirement level="pilot">You should include a title for each distribution within the documentation so reusers know how to refer to it.</requirement>
							</option>
							<option value="description">
								<label>description</label>
								<requirement level="pilot">You should include a description of each distribution within the documentation so reusers know what it contains.</requirement>
							</option>
							<option value="issued">
								<label>release date</label>
								<requirement level="pilot">You should include a release date for each distribution within the documentation so that reusers know how current it is.</requirement>
							</option>
							<option value="modified">
								<label>modification date</label>
								<requirement level="standard">You should include the last modification date for each distribution within the documentation so reusers know whether their copy of it is up to date.</requirement>
							</option>
							<option value="license">
								<label>licence</label>
								<requirement level="standard">You should include a reference to the licence or waiver that applies to each distribution within the documentation so reusers know what they can do with the data.</requirement>
							</option>
							<option value="accessURL">
								<label>URL for accessing the data</label>
								<help>This metadata should be used when the distribution is not a download (eg if it's a pointer to an API)</help>
							</option>
							<option value="downloadURL">
								<label>URL for downloading the dataset</label>
							</option>
							<option value="byteSize">
								<label>size in bytes</label>
							</option>
							<option value="mediaType">
								<label>media type of the download</label>
							</option>
						</checkboxset>
					</question>
				</if>
			</if>
			<if test="this.releaseType() === 'service'">
				<question id="serviceDocumentation">
					<label>Where is the documentation for the API?</label>
					<input type="url" />
					<requirement level="pilot">You should provide documentation about how the API works so that reusers can find out how to use it.</requirement>
				</question>
			</if>
			<question id="vocabulary">
				<label>Do the data formats use vocabularies?</label>
				<yesno required="standard" />
				<help>Formats such as JSON, XML or Turtle provide a generic syntax and need to be supplemented with a schema for developers to understand it.</help>
			</question>
			<if test="this.vocabulary() === 'true'">
				<question id="schemaDocumentationUrl">
					<label>Where is the documentation for the vocabularies?</label>
					<input type="url" />
					<requirement level="standard">You should provide documentation for any vocabulary you use within the data you publish so that reusers know how to interpret the data.</requirement>
				</question>
			</if>
			<question id="codelists">
				<label>Are there any codes used within the data?</label>
				<yesno required="standard" />
				<help>Data often includes codes for things like geographical areas, spending categories or diseases; these codes need to be explained for reusers.</help>
			</question>
			<if test="this.codelists() === 'true'">
				<question id="codelistDocumentationUrl">
					<label>Where are the codes documented?</label>
					<input type="url" />
					<requirement level="standard">You should provide documentation for the codes used within your data so that reusers know how to interpret the data.</requirement>
				</question>
			</if>
		</group>
		<group id="support">
			<label>Support</label>
			<help>giving reusers contact with people who can help them</help>
			<question id="contactEmail">
				<label>What's the contact email address for questions about this data?</label>
				<input type="email" placeholder="Contact Email Address"/>
				<help>Provide an email address that people can contact with queries about the data.</help>
				<requirement level="pilot">You should have a contact email address so that people can get in touch with you about any questions about the data.</requirement>
			</question>
			<question id="forum">
				<label>Where do you recommend people discuss this dataset?</label>
				<input type="url" placeholder="Forum or Mailing List URL"/>
				<help>Provide a URL for the forum or mailing list where developers using this dataset should discuss it.</help>
				<requirement level="standard">You should indicate a place where people using this dataset should discuss the data so that they can support each other.</requirement>
			</question>
			<if test="this.corrected() === 'true'">
				<question id="correctionReporting">
					<label>Where do you describe how to provide corrections?</label>
					<input type="url" placeholder="Correction Instructions URL" />
					<help>Provide a link to a page that describes how people should provide corrections if they discover errors in  the data.</help>
					<requirement level="standard">You should provide instructions for people who discover errors in the data so that they know how to report them.</requirement>
				</question>
				<question id="correctionDiscovery">
					<label>Where do you describe how to learn about corrections?</label>
					<input type="url" placeholder="Correction Notification URL" />
					<help>Provide a link to a page that describes how corrections will be communicated to reusers of the data.</help>
					<requirement level="standard">You should provide an announcement mailing list or a feed to which reusers can subscribe to learn of corrections to the data so that they can keep their local copies up to date.</requirement>
				</question>
			</if>
			<if test="this.dataPersonal() === 'personal' || this.dataPersonal() === 'possibly'">
				<question id="dataProtectionEmail">
					<label>What's the contact email address for confidentiality concerns?</label>
					<input type="email" placeholder="Confidentiality Contact Email Address" />
					<requirement level="pilot">You should provide a contact email address so that reusers with concerns about disclosure of personal details within the data can get in touch.</requirement>
				</question>
			</if>
		</group>
		<group id="services">
			<label>Services</label>
			<help>providing reusers with tools to help work with the data</help>
			<question id="libraries">
				<label>Where do you list tools for working with the data?</label>
				<input type="url" placeholder="Tool URL"/>
				<help>Provide a link to a page that lists the tools that people and developers can use when working with the data.</help>
				<requirement level="exemplar">You should provide a list of software libraries and other tools that help developers who want to work with the data so that reusers can find and reuse them rather than building them from scratch.</requirement>
			</question>
		</group>
	</group>
	-->
	</certificate>
</questionnaire>